Sync by
지노
jin5a@naver.com
Earth, birthplace of the human race,
지구
인류의 고향...
a species much like our own,
우리와 닮은 그들은
capable of great compassion
따뜻한
동정심도 있지만
기원전 17,000년
and great violence.
폭력적이기도 하다
For in our quest to protect the humans,
인류를
보호하기 위해
a deeper revelation dawns.
우리들은 오래 전에
만났다는 걸
Our worlds have met before.
이제는 밝혀야 하리라
트랜스포머: 패자의 역습
(Transformers: Revenge Of The Fallen, 2009)
중국 상해
오늘 밤 10시 14분
-Newsflash from the BBC.
-Breaking news out of Shanghai.
- 뉴스를 말씀 드립니다
- 방금 들어온 속보입니다
There's been a major toxic spill
in the Shanghai factory district.
상해 공장지대에서
유독물질이 유출됐습니다
We're staying
on top of this developing story for you.
소식이 들어오는 대로
We will bring you
any new information as we get it.
전해드리겠습니다
미 국방성
트랜스포머 작전본부
NEST Seahawks approaching target.
'씨호크', 타겟 접근 중!
Three minutes
until evacuation is complete, sir.
대피완료
3분 전입니다
Chinese airspace has been locked
and sealed, one-mile radius.
중국 영공 봉쇄
반경 1마일!
All right, give NEST team the go.
작전 개시해
Black Hawks, you're clear to land.
'블랙 호크', 착륙하라
Ding-a-ling!
Come out and get your ice cream.
뛰뛰빵빵
아이스크림이 왔습니다
Any bad robot out there
better get ready for an ass-whupping.
나쁜 로봇은
혼날 줄 알아요
For the last two years,
an advance team of new Autobots
지난 2년간
'오토봇' 선발팀은
has taken refuge here
under my command.
내 명령에 따라
이곳에 숨어 지냈다
Arcees, get ready to launch.
'알씨', 준비!
We're locked and loaded.
몸 좀 풀어보자
Together, we form an alliance
with the humans,
우리와 동맹을
맺은 인간들은
a secret but brave squad of soldiers.
용감한
비밀부대원들이다
All right, listen up. China's cover story
on this one is "toxic spill."
중국에선 유독물 유출로 꾸며
They had to evac the area
for search and rescue.
지역을 봉쇄시켰다
This makes six enemy contacts
in eight months.
8개월간 적이
6번 나타났지만
We gotta make sure this one does not
get out in the public eye, so keep it tight.
기밀로 해야 하므로
조심하기 바란다
A classified strike team called NEST.
트랜스포머
작전팀은
We hunt for what remains
of our Decepticon foes
남아있는 '디셉티콘'을
찾아내기 위해
hiding in different countries
around the globe.
전 세계 각나라에
숨어 있다
Roll in Alpha through Echo now.
A팀부터
E팀까지 보내
Move out! Let's go!
출동하자!
All right, lronhide.
We got echoes. They're close.
'아이언하이드', 그들이
레이더에 잡힌 곳은
Steel stacks at 2 o'clock.
2시 방향
배기관이야
He's here. l smell him.
그가 왔어
느껴져
lt's close. lt's getting closer.
놈들이 온다!
-Oh, no.
-What have you got?
- 안 돼
- 어때?
Thermal ripple.
열이 감지돼요
Right, everybody, be steady.
We're right on top of it.
다들 준비해
아주 가까이 있다
Eagle niner!
'이글 9'!
l need an energy proton.
수송차 보내!
Panther 1 , requesting fire mission now!
'팬더 1', 속히
미사일 발사하라!
Gunships on station. Roll in hot!
무장 헬기 정 위치!
Dog 1, now we are engaging.
'도그 1', 투입!
We got a second Decepticon.
조심해, 간다!
Arcee twins! Target coming your way!
'알씨', '트윈스'
그쪽이야!
l got him, l got him!
나한테 맡겨줘
놈은 내 거야!
l screwed that up. l'm okay. l'm all right.
내가 다 망쳤군
암튼 난 멀쩡해
-This is combat, man.
-Total brain freeze, man.
조심 좀 하자!
싸움도 못해서
이 꼴로 만들어?!
What's wrong with you?
Bring in Sideswipe!
'사이드스와이프'
불러!
Clear a path!
비켜라!
Damn, l'm good!
나 아직 안 죽었어
Air support, we need Big Buddha
to deliver the drop now!
'빅 부다', 당장
그를 데려와!
Cyclone 98, final attack hitting in 120.
'사이클론 98'
최후공격!
Clear to drop in
five, four, three, two, one.
낙하 5초 전, 4초
3, 2, 1!
Autobots, l'm in pursuit!
'오토봇'들아
내가 가겠다!
Pull over!
세워라!
Punk-ass Decepticon!
가소로운 '디셉티콘'!
Any last words?
남길 말이라도?
This is not your planet to rule!
여긴 너희들이
활개칠 행성이 아냐
The Fallen shall rise again.
'폴른'이 다시
나타날 테니까
That doesn't sound good.
심상치가 않은데요
Not today.
아직은 아니다
Come on, let's go! All hands on deck!
전원 밖으로 집합!
Frankie, Mojo, out!
Come on, kiddo, we're on a schedule.
'프랭키', '모조', 나와!
계획에 착수하자
Slow down, Dad. Why are you
in such a hurry to get rid of me?
왜 이렇게 빨리 쫓아내요?
-Did you rent the room out?
-No, l got other ideas for your room
- 방 세놨어요?
- 실은 네 방에
and it rhymes with "home theater."
홈 시어터 놓으려고
Look what l found.
lt's your little baby booties.
이거 좀 보렴
너 애기 때 신발이야
-Ma.
-My little baby-bootie boy.
- 엄마...
- 우리 이쁜 애기
-You can't go.
-You see this, Dad? This is how
- 못 보낸다
- 봤죠, 아빠?
you're supposed to react
when the fruit of your loins
자식이 험한 세상에
뛰어들 땐
goes out into the cruel world
to fend for himself, okay?
이쯤은 나와줘야죠
Yeah, my heart bleeds for you, pal.
College, bummer!
대학엘 가다니
가슴이 찢어져
You have to come home every holiday,
not just big ones.
휴일마다 와야 돼
띄엄띄엄 오지 말고
You have to come home for Halloween.
할로윈 땐 꼭 와
Well, l can't
come home for Halloween, Mom.
안 돼요
-Well, then we'll come to you.
-You're not coming.
그럼 우리가 갈게
-No, we're not going anywhere.
-We'll dress up.
가긴 어딜!
We'll be in costumes.
You'll never know it's us.
가서 깜짝
놀래켜줄래
-You can't do that, Mom.
-Would you let the kid breathe,
애 좀 놔둘래?
for crying out loud? Come on. Go pack.
가서 한 달 여행할
짐이나 싸라고
There's no way you're packed
for a month-long trip.
Come on, chop, chop!
Let's go. March, young lady.
가세요, 아가씨
-Dad.
-l love it when you call me "young lady,"
아가씨라고 하면 설레잖아
-you dirty old man.
-You ain't seen nothing yet.
- 이 응큼쟁이야
- 쭉 설레고 있어
-Dad, Dad, Dad, whoa!
-What?
- 아빠
- 왜?
l'm watching what you're doing, Dad.
lt's not a rap video.
완전
성인비디오예요
lt's just like a coach thing.
교육용이지
That was
a really creepy move just now, Dad.
교육적이진
않았거든요
Look. You know, your mother and me
are really proud of you.
엄마 아빤 네가
참 자랑스럽다
You're the first Witwicky
ever to go to college.
대학물을 다 먹고!
Now l'm crying again! This sucks!
자꾸만 울컥해!
미치겠네!
You're gonna be okay, Ma.
괜찮아질 거예요
You know, it's just going to be,
엄마로선...
you know, hard for her to accept
that her boy's all grown up, you know,
아들이 다 컸다는 게
받아들이기 힘든 거야
going out to handle the world
on his own.
세상에 혼자
나간다는 게
-You okay, Pop?
-Yeah.
아빤 괜찮죠?
Mojo, no dominating Frankie!
'모조', 어딜 올라타!
Get the hell off the couch,
you filthy beasts!
내려와
이 드러운 놈들아!
You'll see a lot of that in college, too.
대학 가면 저 포즈
많이 봐
-What are you talking about, Dad?
-There's gonna be a lot of women there.
- 무슨 소리예요?
- 여자들 천지라고
Yeah, well,
l'm a one-woman kind of guy.
전 바람 안 피워요
Look, Mikaela's the greatest,
미카엘라도 좋지만
but you gotta give each other
room to grow, okay?
경험도 좀 해봐야지
You're no different
than any other couple your age.
네 또래들은 그래
Except we discovered
an alien race together.
외계 로봇을 같이 본
사이인걸요
How long you gonna be riding
that scooter?
그게 언제까지 갈까?
Dad, listen, l know what the odds are.
We're the exception, okay?
멀어질 수도 있겠지만
우린 달라요
Wait a second. Who could that be?
잠깐
양반 되긴 글렀네
ln two weeks, it could be Muffy.
얼마나 가나 보자
Hey, beautiful.
안녕, 우리 이쁜이
-l'm breaking up with you, Sam.
-Really?
나 너랑 헤어질래
You sure?
l'm not hearing a lot of conviction.
또 장난하네
Well, l am, okay? So, there's no reason
for me to come say good-bye to you.
진짜야
그래서 배웅도 안 하려고
Wow, you almost sounded serious
that time.
너 연기력 점점 는다
Guess what? l made you
a long-distance relationship kit.
있잖아
장거리 연애를 위해
Yeah, l got you a webcam,
so we can chat 24/7.
웹캠까지 보냈거든
24시간 대기할게
All Witwicky, all the time.
And l got you a couple souvenirs
from the event
전화론 말 못할
that cannot be mentioned
on cell phones.
그날 밤 기념품으로
-Some mixes and candles and stuff.
-Sounds cute. l can't wait.
- CD랑 향초도 넣었어
- 빨리 보고 싶다
Hey! You want
the infamous D-Day shirt?
디데이 셔츠도 줄까?
You kept your nasty, shredded clothes?
그 더러운 옷을
갖고 있어?
Yeah. Of course, l kept it, Mikaela.
그럼, 내 피와 땀이 밴
전투복인걸
lt's like my Super Bowl jersey.
l bled in this thing.
-Wow. You're pretty confident, huh?
-No, it's not that.
- 자신만만하네
- 아냐
lt's just that my low self-esteem's
at an all-time high.
없는 자신감
긁어 모으고 있어
You think your little box of souvenirs
is gonna keep me from leaving you?
기념품으로
날 붙잡겠다?
You really should come with me.
같이 가자
They got cheap apartments
near campus.
학교 근처에 싼 아파트 많아
Well, that's not gonna happen
until l get my man-child father,
철부지 아빠가
감옥에서 막 나왔으니
fresh out of prison, back on his feet.
자리 잡는 건 봐야지
l heard that.
Where'd you put the clutch covers?
다 들었다
클러치커버는?
-Next to the camshafts.
-l love it when you say "camshafts."
- 회전축 옆에요
- 그 말 끈적 버전으로
Whisper it to me.
속삭여줘
Camshafts.
회전축...
Why can't l hate you?
미워할 수가 없어!
lt's my Witwicky charm.
매력덩이니까
Wait, hold on. Wait, hold on a second.
잠깐
l guess we're not breaking up.
l'll be over in 20.
못 헤어지겠다
빨리 끝내고 갈게
Mikaela, l think a sliver of the Cube
got stuck on my shirt.
미카엘라, 큐브 조각이
내 셔츠에 붙어 있었어
Sam?
샘?
There's a fire!
불이야!
Dad, we got a fire!
아빠, 불났어요!
Fire!
불이야!
Ron, did you know
it was gonna be this hard?
이렇게 힘들 줄
알았어?
Can you just stop?
1절만 좀 하지?
Yeah, okay, l'll stop. You carry this shit!
알았으니까
이거나 날라!
-Wow.
-Do you know what?
나 당신하고 안 가
-What?
-l don't want to go anywhere with you.
l don't wanna go to France with you.
프랑스든 요 옆이든!
l don't wanna go
around the corner with you.
-l'm going back inside.
-All right, fine.
들어갈래
l'll call you from Paris.
파리에서 전화할게
What is all the racket?
이게 다 무슨 소리야?
Sam?
샘?
Dad!
아빠!
분수!
-What was that?
-That's the whole kitchen!
- 뭐야?!
- 주방기기요!
-Bumblebee... Oh, my...
-Bumblebee!
'범블비'!
-91 1 .
-Bumblebee!
- 119!
- '범블비'!
-Get in the garage. Go!
-What the freak just happened?
- 차고에 들어가
- 다 뭐니?
l'm about to have a nervous breakdown.
Just go in the garage quietly, please.
정신 없으니까
얌전히 들어가 있어
Holy Mother!
세상에나!
-Oh, my God!
-Whatever.
- 맙소사!
- 됐거든
Get in the garage now!
차고에 들어가
어서!
-Firemen! Fire fighters, over here!
-Dogs out! Get the dogs out!
개 좀 데리고 나와!
This is it! Come on, you guys.
What are you waiting for?
여기예요
빨리 좀 와요!
My house is on fire!
우리 집에 불났어요!
-...very important.
-What happened?
- 중요한 거야
- 무슨 일이야?
Come here. Listen, l need you to take
the Cube sliver and put it in your purse.
이리 와
큐브 조각부터 가방에 넣어
-What's going on?
-Just take it.
- 뭐?
- 어서
-Sam Witwicky? A word with you.
-Yes, Mom. Yeah.
샘 윗위키?
얘기 좀 할까?
-Hi, Mikaela. l have a bald spot.
-Hi.
미카엘라
나 땜통 생겼다
-An old furnace, l think.
-From a waffle iron.
- 난로에서 났어요
- 와플 기계야
When you go, he goes. l cannot live
with a psychotic alien in my garage!
쟤도 데려가
나 싸이코 로봇 못 키워
Judy... National security.
여보, 쉿!
국가기밀이야
Look, if we stay quiet,
they're gonna take care of everything.
가만 있으면
정부가 알아서 할 거야
Just consider this
the official start of our remodel, okay?
이 기회에
리모델링 하지, 뭐
Fine. lf the government's paying,
l want a pool and a hot tub!
정부가 쏜다면 풀장도 만들래
실외욕조도!
And l'm gonna skinny-dip
and you can't say shit about it!
거기서 반신욕도
할 거야
-Yeah, you know you're in trouble.
-He still having voice problems?
- 그래, 너 큰일 났다
- 여태 목소리 안 나와?
He's playing it up.
쥐어짜고 있어
Bee, l want to talk to you
about the college thing, okay?
'범블비'
나 대학 가는 거 알지?
l'm so excited and l just can't hide it
♪ 이 흥분되는 기분
♪ 감출수가 없네
Hey, l'm not taking you with me.
너 못 데려가
l'm gonna wait outside, okay?
난 나가 있을게
l meant to tell you about this earlier.
곧 말하려고 했는데
lt's just that, you know...
Here's the thing.
어떻게 된 거냐면
Freshmen aren't allowed to have cars.
신입생은 차 못 몬대
l know, and if it was up to me,
l'd take you with me, but it's not, Bee.
마음 같아선 데려가고 싶지만
힘들게 됐어
Look. You're an Autobot. You shouldn't
be living in my dad's garage.
넌 '오토봇'이야
l mean, you're suffocating in here.
You deserve better than this.
차고에서 살다간 숨막혀 죽어
그럼 안 되잖아
This is hard enough, man.
Don't make it harder.
어렵게 얘기하는 건데
나 좀 봐줄래?
Can you just look at me, please?
기분 풀어라
Come on, big guy.
Look, the guardian thing is done.
그동안 내 보디가드
잘해줬어
Okay? You did yourjob.
Look, l'm safe now.
이제 난 안전하니까
You need to go be with
Optimus Prime and the others.
'옵티머스'한테 돌아가
l just want to be normal, Bee.
That's why l'm going to college,
평범하게 살려고
대학 가는 거라
and l can't do that with you.
네가 있으면 안 돼
lt's not the last time l'm gonna see you,
you know, Bee.
나중에 또 만나자
Come on, don't do that. Bee.
You're killing me, Bee.
그러지 마, '범블비'
그럼 나도 슬프잖아
But you'll always be my first car.
넌 영원한 내 첫 차야
Love you, Bee.
사랑한다
Wow!
와아!
Between State Farm and the taxpayers,
we're all taken care of.
보험사든 정부든
해결해줄 거야
-You got dirt all over you.
-Stop. Stop.
- 뭐 묻었어
- 됐어, 괜찮아
-What?
-Stop, l'm okay.
Look.
저 봐
So, you think you can make it through
those East Coast winters without me?
나 없이 그 추운 겨울을
날 수 있겠어?
You're the best thing
to ever happen to me.
넌 최고의 선물이야
-And?
-And l'll do anything for you.
- 그리고?
- 널 위해선 뭐든 할게
And?
그리고?
-l think Sam's about to say the L-word.
-Let's go, kiddo!
- 사랑고백 하려나 봐
- 가자!
Nice timing, Dad.
타이밍 죽여주셔
l adore you.
널 좋아해
That's not the word that l want
그 말이 아닌데
-to hear right now.
-What are you talking about?
그거나 그거나
lt's the same word as the other word.
-lt's not the same word.
-Look, if l say the other word now
- 엄연히 달라
- 그걸 꼭 말로 해야 돼?
and you forced me to say it,
it won't mean anything, plus
또, 너도 말 안 했잖아
you haven't said it either.
So, don't get mad at me for not saying it.
Yeah, but l haven't said it because guys
always run when you say it first.
여자 먼저 그럼
도망칠걸
Yeah, well, so do girls.
Especially girls like you, with options.
남 말하네
너같이 완벽한 앤 더 심하지
So, this is all part of your elaborate plan
to keep me interested?
겨우 이걸로
날 붙잡아두시겠다?
-lt can be.
-l hate that it's working.
- 그러려고
- 또 넘어가네
Can l have a kiss?
키스해도 돼?
We're going to make it work, l promise.
우린 잘해낼 거야
여자가 큐브 조각을
갖고 있다
Soundwave acknowledges. Pursue her.
여긴 '사운드웨이브', 알았다
Retrieve it.
따라가서 찾아와라
트랜스포머 작전기지
디에고 가르시아 섬
Autobot twins, report to Hangar Three.
'오토봇 트윈스'
3번 집결지로!
Bad-ass ice-cream truck
coming through.
아이스크림 차 나갑니다
-Excuse me! Excuse me! Hello!
-No, l don't...
비켜요!
-Hold up.
-Those are nice.
잘 빠졌는걸
Yeah, baby, it's upgrade time.
우리도 업그레이드하자
Yes, sir. Yeah!
Look here, it's my booty call right here!
좋지
난 쟤가 맘에 들어
-Time to get my sexy on with the green.
-Green? No, green is mine!
- 초록색 애랑 잘해볼래
- 안돼, 걘 내 거야
l call green!
내가 찜했다고
-l got the green.
-That hurt, man.
- 양보해
- 아파
lt's supposed to hurt. lt's an ass-kicking.
아프라고 때렸거든
Present arms!
받들어 총!
Director Galloway, what an honor.
l'd love to show you around,
갤로웨이 보좌관님
여긴 기밀지역입니다
but you gotta be
on the classified access list.
l am now. Presidential order, Major.
대통령 명령서네
l got a message
for your classified space buddies!
외계 로봇 친구들에게
소식을 갖고 왔지
You guys made a mess of Shanghai.
상해가
쑥대밭이 됐더군
All right, so this is where
we communicate with the JCS
여긴 합동참모부
관할이며
and this area serves
as the Autobots' hangar.
'오토봇' 집결지죠
Secure link to JCS is up, Major.
합동참모부
연결했습니다
미 군사위성
Secure line to
the Pentagon is now open.
국방성입니다
-General?
-Will, I saw the Shanghai op.
- 장군님?
- 상해 작전은
-We had a rough day out there.
-Yes, sir.
- 힘들었겠더군
- 네
We have intel that I believe
warrants an immediate debrief.
결과 보고에 있어선
Now with your permission,
l can't let you see him,
'오토봇' 리더가 친히
들려드리겠습니다
but l would like you to hear
from the leader of the Autobots.
Proceed.
그러게
You gotta wonder,
신의 모습을 본따...
if God made us in his image,
who made him?
우릴 만드셨다면
저들은 누가 만들었을까요?
General, our alliance
has countermanded
장군, 우린 올해
각 대륙에 걸친
six Decepticon incursions this year,
'디셉티콘' 공격을
each on a different continent.
6번이나 막아냈죠
They're clearly searching
around the world for something,
그들은 뭔가를 찾아
뒤지고 있는 겁니다
but last night's encounter
came with a warning.
어제는
경고까지 했죠
"The Fallen shall rise again."
'폴른'이 다시
나타날 거라고
"The Fallen." Meaning what?
'폴른'이 뭡니까?
Origin unknown.
The only recorded history of our race
기원은 모르나
우리 역사는
was contained within the AllSpark
and lost with its destruction.
큐브에 담겨 있고
그게 파괴되면서 사라졌죠
Excuse me!
잠깐!
With this so-called AllSpark
now destroyed,
큐브라는 게
파괴된 지금
why hasn't the enemy left the planet
like you thought they would?
왜 아직 적들이
지구에 남아 있는 거지?
Director Galloway,
our National Security Advisor.
갤로웨이 국가안보 보좌관을
The Presidentjust appointed him liaison.
대통령께서 보내셨습니다
Well, l guess l didn't get that memo.
그런 일은
금시초문이군
Forgive the interruption, General.
Excuse me. Coming through.
방해해서 죄송합니다
좀 지나가세
Excuse me. Excuse me, soldier.
비켜주게
After all the damage in Shanghai,
상해가 초토화되고 보니
the President is hard-pressed
to say the job's getting done.
대통령께선 임무실패를
염려하시죠
Now, under the classified Alien/Autobot
Cooperation Act,
사실, 기밀 '오토봇'
협력법에 따라
you agreed to share your intel with us,
but not your advancements in weaponry.
정보를 우리와 나누기로 했으나
무기는 예외로 했지
We've witnessed
your human capacity for war.
인간의 전쟁능력을
봐 온 이상
lt would absolutely bring
more harm than good.
득보단 실이
많기 때문이죠
But who are you to judge
what's best for us?
당신이 뭔데
그걸 판단하지?
With all due respect,
we've been fighting side by side
저흰 2년간
함께 싸워왔습니다
in the field for two years.
We've shed blood,
sweat and precious metal together.
우린 피와 땀과 쇳조각을
함께 흘렸어요
Soldier, you're paid to shoot, not talk.
자넨 입 다물고
총이나 쏘게
Don't tempt me.
확 쏘고 싶네요
And the newest members of your team.
당신네 신입 팀원들!
-Easy.
-l understand they arrived here
- 진정해
- 당신이 우주에다
after you sent a message into space,
지구로 와달란 전갈을
an open invitation to come to Earth,
vetted by no one at the White House.
멋대로 보냈고
그래서 왔다던데
Let me stop you right there,
Mr. Galloway. lt was vetted right here.
그만 하시오
다 검토한 사안이니까
And in my experience, the judgment
of both Major Lennox and his team
내 경험상 레녹스 소령
부대원들은
has always been above reproach.
늘 나무랄 데가
없었소
Well, be that as it may, General,
it is the position of the President
대통령께선 생각이
다르십니다
that when our national security is
at stake, no one is above reproach.
국가를 위험에 처하게 했다면
나무랄 데가 있는 거라고
Now, what do we know so far?
그럼 정리해볼까요?
We know that the enemy leader,
classified NBE One, aka Megatron,
적의 리더는 알죠
오래 전 발견됐던 '메가트론'은
is rusting in peace at the bottom
of the Laurentian Abyssal,
로렌시아 심연에서
편히 녹슬고 있으며
surrounded by SOSUS detection nets
and a full-time submarine surveillance.
이걸 우린 24시간
감시하고 있습니다
We also know that the only remaining
piece of your alien AllSpark
또한 외계 로봇의
큐브 잔해는
is locked in an electromagnetic vault
세계에서 가장
안전한 이곳
here on one of the most secure
naval bases in the worId.
전자기 저장실에 보관했죠
Decepticons, we have located the shard.
'디셉티콘', 큐브 조각
위치를 알아냈다
And since no one can seem to tell me
what the enemy is now after,
지금 적들이 노리는 게
뭔지 모른다면
well, there's only one clear conclusion!
결론은 단 하나!
You! The Autobots!
당신네 '오토봇'들!
They're here to hunt you!
당신들을
잡으러 왔겠지!
What's there to hunt for on Earth
besides that?
그게 아니면 뭐겠어?
"The Fallen shall rise again"?
'폴른'이 다시 나타나?
lt sounds to me
like something's coming.
그럼 뭔가 오겠군
So, let me ask, if we ultimately conclude
that our national security is best served
하나만 묻지
만일 우리의 안전을 위해
by denying you further asylum
on our planet,
지구에 머무는 걸
허락할 수 없다면
will you leave peacefully?
조용히 떠나주겠나?
Freedom is your right. lf you make
that request, we will honor it.
자유는 당신들 권리요
그걸 원한다면 따라야죠
But before your President decides,
please ask him this.
허나... 결정하기에 앞서
대통령께 이걸 물어주십시오
What if we leave and you're wrong?
우리가 떠나는 게
과연 옳은가?
That's a good question.
좋은 질문이에요
Oh, my gosh! Look at this place!
세상에, 여기 좀 봐!
l feel smarter already.
막 똑똑해지는 거
같아
-Ron, can you smell it?
-Yeah, smells like $40,000 a year.
- 론, 이 냄새 맡고 있어?
- 등록금 냄새가 물씬 나네
-Hey, cheapo!
-Hey, go ahead. We'll get your stuff.
- 하여간 구두쇠야
- 우린 짐 갖고 갈게
Just go ahead and check out your room.
먼저 가서 방부터 봐
Yeah, go.
-Hey.
-You must be Sam, right? l'm Leo.
샘이구나
나 레오야
So, l already set up the crib a bit.
You want this side or that side?
방 꾸미고 있는데
이쪽 쓸래, 저쪽 쓸래?
-That side.
-l already chose that side.
- 저쪽!
- 거긴 내가 쓸 거야
You know what this is?
This is the awkward moment.
이거 되게 뻘쭘하다
Yeah, see,
you're trying to see if l'm a normal guy.
지금 서로 간 보잖아
l'm trying to see if you're a normal guy.
제정신은 박혔나
Balanced, unmedicated,
nothing under the crawl space.
Good personal hygiene,
won't stab me in my sleep.
잘 씻고
해코지 안 하나
No criminal record, won't steal anything.
훔치진 않나
-lncluding girlfriends.
-Especially girlfriends.
- 여친 포함해서!
- 기본이지
-You got a girlfriend?
-l do. You?
- 여친 있어?
- 응, 넌?
No, not a chance. You a techie?
아직, 컴퓨터 좀 해?
Sweet! Sharsky,
Fassbinder, where we at?
좋았어
샤스키, 파스빈더, 잘돼 가?
-Server's almost online, Leo.
-Network's up and running.
- 서버 연결 중!
- 다 됐어
Beautiful, that's what l like to hear.
좋아
That's Sharsky, that's Fassbinder,
my lT gurus.
샤스키랑 파스빈더
lT고수들이야
Welcome to my empire, bro,
TheRealEffingDeal.com.
나의 웹 제국 '초대박.com'
들어는 봤겠지?
That's me, l'm sure you've heard of it.
-No, l haven't.
-Well, that sucks.
- 전혀
- 너무하네
-What is all this for?
-See where l'm going, bro.
- 다 뭔데?
- 봐 봐
Look, call me gross,
l want to be a baby billionaire.
난 소년
억만장자가 될 거야
Kitten calendars.
That's where l started. Look at me now.
짠, 야옹이 달력!
시작은 미약했으나 지금의 날 봐
Got to have dreams, bro.
Leo! We got
some brand-new Shanghai vid!
레오, 따끈한
상해 영상이야
Post it, baby! Go, go, go! FTJ! FTJ!
당장 올려, 빨리!
일빠로!
-What's "FTJ"?
-"Fuel the Jet."
- '일빠'가 뭐야?
- 일등으로 올리라고
Fuel the Jet, bro.
FTJ. FTJ, legit!
완전 대박이다!
Did you see that? Did you see that?
봤어?
Look at this. Half of Shanghai gets
wrecked and China says "gas leak."
상해 반이 아작났는데
가스 누출이래
Don't believe the hype, bro.
Just like the alien robots in LA
two years ago that everyone covered up.
2년 전 L.A. 로봇 출현처럼
눈가리고 아웅이지
Yeah, l saw these robots,
and they did this, like, firing thing
그 로봇들 봤는데
막 쏴대고
and they came down and toasted
this woman, and she was like...
여자를 불태웠어
-lt looks fake to me.
-Dude, it's not fake.
- 합성 같다
- 합성 아냐
The lnternet is pure truth.
Video doesn't lie.
인터넷은 사기 안 쳐
-lt looks fake.
-No, man, l've seen them.
- 합성 같은데, 뭐
- 내가 봤는데 로봇이었어
-They're, like, these robots...
-Look, look, it's fake.
Anybody could do it
on any computer, okay?
저쯤은 다 만들어
And l wasn't there,
난 거기 없었으니
-so l can't comment or speculate.
-No.
가타부타 말할 수 없지
"Comment or speculate"?
And we're supposed to cohabitate?
가타부타?
근데 나랑 한방을 써?
No, listen, okay?
Don't be sucking the sack, bro!
머릴 쓰면서 살아라
-Which sack?
-The ball sack.
- 무슨 머리?
- 잔머리!
Dude, what kind of tool are you?
머린 장식이냐?
Mainstream media sack.
They're lying to us, all right?
뉴스면 다 믿나 본데
순 뻥이야
-lt's aliens, man.
-Okay, okay.
외계 로봇 맞다고
Follow me.
따라와 봐
Leo, bad news!
레오, 한발 늦었어
We just got scooped.
The video's already up on GFR.
벌써 딴 사이트에 떴다고
Fassbinder!
Robo-Warrior, the guy's our main
competition on conspiracy stuff.
로보워리어, 이 자식이
내 사이트도 흉내내더니
"Effing" was my F-ing idea
and he stole it!
별걸 다 훔쳐가
He's been linking to my site
and thieving hits forever.
네 파일 봤는데
By the way, l read your file.
l'm poor, you're poor.
가난도 면할 겸
We're gonna fix that, all right?
You work for me now.
내 밑에서 일해라
l work for you now? That's incredible.
네 밑에서?
lt's first day of college,
l got a career in a dinky lnternet firm
대학 첫날부터 허접한
인터넷 회사에 취직하다니
with a boss who is made up
ofjust pure champion stuff.
사장님 성격도
참 좋고
Are you mocking
my life's work, Samuel?
지금 나 씹냐?
That's your one warning patrolling,
dude. Don't make me
당장 해킹해서
have Fassbinder hack your financial aid,
'cause l'll do it!
네 장학금 취소시킨다!
Hey, RA. Listen, it's getting a little
intense in my room. Can l switch out?
혹시 룸메이트
바꿀 수 있어요?
Sad face, 31 2. No switching, no trading.
Let's turn that frown upside down, okay?
312호 학생
교환불가니까 인상 펴
-Oh, here we go.
-We made it. Hi.
lt's just like Hogwarts.
해리포터의
마법학교 같아
-Hi.
-ls this co-ed?
This is a co-ed dorm.
남녀공용이야
-You guys want to meet my roommates?
-Yeah.
룸메이트 보실래요?
Some real swell guys.
굉장한 애들인데
-Here's Leo.
-We're the Witwickys.
얜 레오예요
-l'm Leo.
-l'm Judy.
주디 윗위키란다
Hey, you have a great son, you really do.
멋진 아드님을
두셨군요
-Well, aren't you the sweetest thing?
-Yeah, he's real sweet, Ma.
- 착하기도 해라
- 착해 빠졌죠
What is that in your hand, by the way?
뭐예요?
l got this at the bake sale for the
environment that those boys are having.
환경모금 한다며
빵을 파는 거 있지
You know, you don't often see
white boys with the dreadlocks.
머리 배배 꼰 애들이
고생하더라
-Mom?
-Yeah, it's 1 00% pure,
100% 하와이산
유기농이래
Hawaiian green for the environment.
-How many of these have you eaten?
-Drop it.
거의 다 드셨네?
-What is this?
-Yeah, they baked it with reefer in it.
대마초 든 것도
모르고
-No, it's...
-Please, give me...
Hey! lt's my cheat day.
l can eat what l want.
오늘은 질리도록
먹어볼래
l'm going to freak out.
Please do something right now, Dad.
미치겠네
아빠, 어떻게 좀 해봐요
Please do something right now.
l can eat all the fricking brownies l want!
나도 빵 먹을
자유쯤은 있다고!
Come on, let's go.
l'm sorry and you're welcome.
어째 상황이 묘하군
We call it the "Hot Freshman 55."
섹시 신입생이
55명이야
Sharsky hacked Campus Housing and
stacked the dorm with pretty Betties.
샤스키가 해킹해서
미녀들 몰아온 보람이 있군
ls... ls so nice...
Oh, my God. That's her. She's coming.
She sees me, she sees me.
쟤 봤어?
나 쳐다보는 거 봐
She's tied for number one
on my to-do list.
내 첫 월척이니까
Do not bird-dog my quail, you hear me?
눈독 들이지 마
Pretty girls! Hey, you.
My son lives in this dorm.
이쁜 언니들?
우리 아들 여기 산다네
You should go make friends with him.
He's Sam.
친구 좀 해줘
샘이란 애야
Glad she ain't my mama!
울 엄마 아니라
다행이야
And he recently had his cherry popped!
총각 딱지도 막 뗐다!
He didn't know l was in the house!
l heard it all!
나 집에 있는 줄
모르고 하대
-Hey! Hey! Hey!
-Here he is!
바로 얘야!
He would get in my closet
and dress up as Boy Spice!
내 옷장 뒤져선
야하게 입는 게 취미인데
-Hey, and his car is a talking robot!
-No, like the GPS. OnStar!
- 차는 말하는 로봇이야!
- GPS 달았어
-OnStar.
-Frisbee!
- 네비게이션도!
- 원반던지기다!
No, Dad! Dad, you just gonna
let her run around the school?
아빠, 엄마 그냥
놔둘 거예요?
-Give it! Mine, mine, mine!
-Hey! Crazy!
내놔!
내 거야, 내 거!
-You want it?
-l want it.
나 할래
Judy, Judy, just... Just put it down.
주디, 그거 내려놔
-You gotta control your mother.
-l don't know who this woman is.
- 엄마 좀 모셔가
- 모르는 아줌마야
Hey, Professor, l'd do anything for an A.
교수님, A 주심
뭐든 할게요
All right, Grace Slick. We got
some snacks in the car. Let's go.
좋지, 늙은 학생!
차로 가자
-Did you get the booties? All right.
-Yes, Dad, l got the booties!
- 신발 챙겼냐?
- 챙겼어요!
l'm upside down!
나 빙빙 돌아!
제한구역
Black Lion X-Ray,
this is Black Lion Tango.
'블랙 라이온'
We have activation of motion sensors
on the western perimeter fence.
서쪽 경계지역에
움직임 감지!
Breach at B-14.
14구역 침입자 발생!
Go, go, go, go!
출동, 출동!
The shard's gone.
조각이 없어졌다
Contact!
침입자 확인!
Take it down!
부숴버려!
-Which way?
-Shoot left!
왼쪽이야!
Knock it down!
없애버려!
First frat party's the game changer.
Boys, we're hunting in the wild now.
사교 파티야말로
판을 뒤집을 수 있는 기회야
So, get your game faces on.
l can't stay long.
l have a webcam date with my girlfriend.
난 여친하고
메신저 해야 돼
-That's so cool!
-No, it's not.
- 좋겠다
- 좋긴 개뿔!
While he's making out
with his MacBook,
얘 컴퓨터 앞에서
죽칠 때
l'm gonna be getting
my Spitzy freaky freak on.
난 온몸을 불사를걸
-Let's roll.
-She's hot.
- 가자
- 쟤 괜찮네
Bro, we're hunting!
헌팅 간다
-See you, darling.
-Bye, Dad.
- 아빠 간다
- 가세요
Okay.
This is our first live chat date.
l've never done it before.
메신저는 처음이야
안 해보던 거라
l'm kind of nervous.
살짝 떨리네
-Are you okay?
-No.
- 괜찮니?
- 아니, 저기...
l was getting a napkin for my drink.
냅킨 좀 집으려고
Thanks. Cheers.
건배!
-lt's Sam, right?
-Yeah.
샘 맞지?
-l wanna dance.
-What, like... Like dancing?
- 춤추자
- 춤 말이야?
Like a pairing? Like a duo?
Like a coupling?
부비부비도 하고?
'Cause l'm in a permanently semi...
l'm in a relationship, kind of...
난 평생을 함께할...
아니, 반평생... 여자친구 있어
-Relax. l just want to have some fun.
-Wanna have some fun?
- 진정해, 같이 놀잔 거뿐이야
- 그냥 놀자고?
Yeah, okay. Let's play some checkers.
You can sit over there and...
좋아, 장기나 두자
넌 저기 앉고...
Oh, my...
So, how about tonight
you pretend l'm your girlfriend
오늘밤만
난 네 여친 하고
and l pretend that you're my boyfriend?
넌 내 남친 해주라
Hey! Who drove
the freaking yellow Camaro?
야!
누가 이 노란 차 끌고 왔어?
There is a car on the lawn!
잔디밭에 있던데!
What are you doing?
웬일이야?
Houston, we have a problem.
휴스턴
문제가 생겼다
-What is it?
-Freshman!
야, 신입!
-Yeah?
-ls that your car in our bushes?
그 차 네 거냐?
No, there's a friend of mine,
he just went to get you a tighter shirt.
내 친구 차, 걘 더 대단한
쫄티 사러 갔어
There isn't a tighter shirt! We checked.
더 쫄릴 수가 없거든!
Now how about
l park my foot in your ass?
내 발차기
맛 좀 볼래?
-What size shoe do you wear?
-Yeah?
맛이 어떤데?
-Hold on.
-You wanna try?
일단 맞아봐
-l'll back it up right now.
-Get him out of here.
차부터 뺄게
You have a ride?
Bro, why are you holding out on us?
너 차 있어?
왜 말 안 했냐?
l've only known you 1 7 hours.
너 안 지 17시간째야
This is gonna really change our lives.
You have no idea.
이제 우리 인생 폈다
-l love Camaros.
-l can't do this right now, okay?
- 난 이런 차 좋더라
- 나 지금 좀 바빠
-Don't be a wimp.
-Oh, God!
소심하긴!
-My first car was my dad's '92 Z28.
-Yeah?
내 첫 차도 아빠가 몰던
이런 차였어
Fuel-injected.
The roar of the engine, it just tickles me.
연료 분사식이고
엔진 소리가 날 흥분시켰지
We shouldn't stare...
그런 매끈한...
l mean, share stories
with each other at all.
아니, 후끈한 얘긴
그만 하자
Come on, Sam. Just one ride.
샘, 한 번만 타자
Your cheatin' heart
바람 피우냐♪
Don't. Don't!
하지 좀 마!
She's a super freak, super freak
She's super freaky
그녀는 막 들이대네
마구 마구 들이대네♪
-ls your radio broken?
-No, my concentration is.
- 라디오 고장났니?
- 내 머리가 고장이야
We're not cheating.
바람 피우는 거 아냐
Not yet.
아직은!
ls something wrong here?
이거 왜 이러니?
God! You okay?
맙소사, 괜찮아?
She's mighty, mighty
l really don't know what to tell you.
This car has a lot of problems. A lot...
얘가 원래
문제가 좀 많아
Oh, God! lt's in my mouth!
입에 들어갔어!
Are you okay? l got Wetnaps.
괜찮아?
물티슈 갖고 올게
l got Wetnaps for your face! Hold on!
기다려
l... l'm so sorry!
정말 미안해
What are you doing?
왜 온 건데?
You won't give me a day, huh?
하루도 못 참아요?
-You won't give me one day in college?
-l'm sorry, Sam,
- 대학생 노릇도 못하게?
- 미안한데
but the last fragment of the AllSpark
was stolen.
큐브의
마지막 조각을 훔쳐갔다
Like what? Like Decepticons stole it?
'디셉티콘'이오?
We placed it under human protection
at your government's request,
정부의 요청에 따라
인간에게 맡겼었는데
but l'm here for your help, Sam,
네가 도와줘야겠다
because your leaders believe we
brought vengeance upon your planet.
너희 리더들은 우리 때문에
디셉티콘이 올 거라고 여겨
Perhaps they are right.
맞을지도 모르지
That is why they must be reminded by
another human of the trust we share.
그래서 더더욱 우리가 믿는
인간이 나서줘야 돼
-This isn't my war.
-Not yet,
- 나완 상관없는 전쟁이에요
- 아직은 그렇지
but l fear it soon will be.
허나 곧 상관 있게 돼
Your world must not share
the same fate as Cybertron.
지구는 사이버트론 행성의
운명을 닮으면 안 되지
Whole generations lost.
우린 전 세대를
잃었다
l know, and l want to help you, l do,
저도 정말로
돕고 싶어요
but l am not some alien ambassador,
you know?
하지만 난
외계 대사가 아닌
l'm a normal kid with normal problems.
평범한 아이라고요
l am where l'm supposed to be.
나설 처지가 못 돼요
l'm sorry. l...
미안해요
l really am.
정말로요
Sam, fate rarely calls upon us
at a moment of our choosing.
샘, 운명은 우리가
원하는 대로 되지 않는다
You're Optimus Prime.
You don't need me.
'옵티머스 프라임' 님인데
내가 뭐 필요해요
We do, more than you know.
필요하다
상상도 못할 만큼!
북대서양</FONT: 7시 13분
토피카 호
원자력잠수함 - 754
Conn, Sonar. Gained new contact,
bearing 214, and possible hostile,
수중음파 감지
적이 나타난 곳은...
confirmed for
Project Deep Six Drop Point.
'디셉티콘'
매장지입니다
-What do you got?
-SU pulled five contacts at 5,000 feet,
1500미터 지점에서
5번 감지됐습니다
diving fast.
Never seen anything
dive that deep that fast.
저렇게 깊고 빠르다니
-Man battle stations.
-Chief of the watch, man battle stations!
- 전군 전투태세!
- 파수병, 전투태세!
Helm, left full rudder,
all ahead two-thirds.
조타수, 왼쪽으로 꺾고
-Left full rudder, two-thirds.
-Dive, go deep.
- 서서히 운행해
- 깊이 내려가
The nets protecting NBE One
are screaming, sir.
'메가트론' 구역, 비상!
That is 9,300 fathoms down.
And no confirmed DSRVs on site?
수심 17킬로
부근에 잠수함은?
-None, sir.
-Then, people, we've got a problem!
- 없습니다
- 그럼 큰일났군!
Need parts! Kill the little one!
부품이 필요하다!
작은 애를 죽여라!
The shard make Energon!
큐브 조각이
에너지를 만든다!
Conn, Sonar. Now hold six contacts,
and they're coming up fast!
6번 감지
빠르게 올라옵니다
-Sound collision alarm.
-Left hard rudder.
- 소리 충돌 경보
- 왼쪽으로 꺾어
Five hundred feet.
150미터!
Angel Six,
we got six hostiles coming up.
'엔젤 6'
적군 여섯이 접근 중!
-Collision imminent port side.
-One hundred feet.
좌측 충돌에
대비하라
Brace for impact.
Starscream, l'm home.
'스타스크림'
내가 왔다
Lord Megatron, l was so relieved
to hear of your resurrection.
'메가트론' 님
살아나셨다니 안심입니다
You left me to die
on that pathetic insect planet.
넌 날 그 쓰레기 행성에서
죽게 놔둔 채 떠났지
Only to help spawn our new army.
The Fallen decrees it!
병력을 정비하려고 그랬죠
이제 '폴른'이 나섰습니다!
After all, in your absence,
someone had to take command.
누군가는 대장 자리를
지켜야 했죠
-So disappointing.
-Hatchlings! Hatchlings! Careful, fragile!
- 참 실망스럽군
- 아직 어리니 조심하십쇼!
Even in death,
there is no command but mine.
죽어서도 대장은
나 하나뿐이다
My master, l failed you on Earth.
사부님, 제가 지구에서
기대를 저버렸죠
The AllSpark is destroyed
and without it, our race will perish.
큐브가 파괴됐으니
우리 종족도 멸망할 겁니다
You have much to learn, my disciple.
The Cube was merely a vessel.
넌 아직도 멀었구나
큐브는 그릇일 뿐이다
lts power, its knowledge,
can never be destroyed.
그 힘, 그 지식은
결코 파괴되지 않는다
-lt can only transform.
-How is that possible?
- 변형될 뿐이지
- 어떻게 그렇죠?
lt has been absorbed
by the human child.
인간 아이에 의해
흡수됐으니
The key to saving our race
now lies within his mind.
우리 종족을 구원할 열쇠는
이제 그의 안에 있다
Well, then, let me strip
the very flesh from his body!
제가 파헤쳐
빼내오겠습니다
And you will, my apprentice, in time.
결코 늦어선 안 된다
For millennia, l have dreamed
of my return to that wretched planet
수천 년 동안 고향행성으로
돌아가는 꿈을 꿨지
where l, too, was once betrayed
by the Primes l called my brothers.
한때는 그곳에서 배신을 당하기도 했다
내 형제인 '프라임'들에게 말이다
Only a Prime can defeat me,
and now, only one remains.
'프라임'만이 날 쳐부술 수 있지
이제 남은 '프라임'은 하나뿐!
Optimus! He protects the boy.
'옵티머스'!
그가 아이를 보호하고 있죠
Then the boy will lead us to him
그럼 그 아이를 따라
그에게 가서
-and revenge will be ours.
-Yes.
복수의 쓴 맛을
보여주리라
The boy will not escape us.
We have him in our sights.
꼬마는 우리 눈에서
벗어날 수 없습니다
Without more Energon,
the hatchlings will keep dying.
에너지를 더 못 구하면
어린 것들이 죽게 되죠
Space. Time. Gravity.
공간, 시간
중력
-Thank you.
-Finish that for me.
- 잘 먹을게요
- 남기면 안 돼
We're going on a journey together,
you and l, today.
오늘 우린
여행을 떠날 거야
All you eager, nubile, young minds
on the very cusp of adulthood.
여러분의 농익은
뜨거운 가슴을 안고
And l shall be your consort, your guide,
난 보호자이자
길잡이가 되어
your chaperone,
into the heart of darkness.
어둠의 세계로
떠나는 거지
Welcome to Astronomy 1 01 .
천문학 수업
잘해보자
For what do we know about the stars?
별에 대해 뭘 알지?
Virgo, the virgin.
처녀궁...
처녀자리!
Orion, the great hunter.
오리온
거대한 사냥꾼!
These are no mere twinkling diamonds
for lovely maidens to wish upon.
이건 단지 소원을 비는
반짝이는 보석이 아냐
No, they are dynamos
힘의 원동력으로
filled with a throbbing,
savage and pent-up energy!
두근대고 격렬하기까지 한
에너지를 담고 있지
Behold the work ofAlbert Einstein,
a professor once, like moi.
아인슈타인의 업적을 봐
한땐 나처럼 교수셨지
-Energy equals mass...
-What you doing?
에너지는 질량에...
Put your hand down.
손 내려
Young man, there are no questions
강의가 절정에
이를 때까지
until l've reached
the climax of my lecture.
질문은 사양한다
l just finished your book and there's
only one problem. Einstein's wrong.
책을 다 읽어보니
아인슈타인이 틀렸어요
Energy does equal
mass times the velocity
에너지는 질량 곱하기
of light squared in this dimension,
광속의 제곱이면 17은요?
but what about the other 1 7?
Nobody ever talks about the other 1 7.
Clear example.
예를 들죠
Break down the elemental components
of Energon,
에너지 성분과
감소율을 분석해서
assume a constant decay rate
and extrapolate for each of the...
Fourteen galactic convergences it took
14개 은하의 집중으로
the Sentinel Prime expedition
to receive an... Echo on its signal,
'프라임'의 탐험을
유추할 때
you wind up with a formula
for inter-dimensional energy increase
질량과 빛만으론
that mass and light alone
can't possibly explain.
성립 안 되는
공식이 나오죠
Come on, guys, l can't be
the only one in the class who...
알아듣는 사람이...
Young man, l will not be
punk'd in front of the dean.
학생, 나 학장님 앞에서
창피당하긴 싫은데
No, this is my universe here.
이건 내 수업이야
Do you understand?
l am the alpha and the omega.
알아듣겠나?
내가 주연이자 조연이지
-Get out of my class!
-Yes, sir.
당장 나가게!
Anyone else care to have
some sort of mental breakdown?
또 제정신 아닌 사람?
Hi, Bones! Hi. Hi.
You're such a good boy.
'본즈', 안녕!
착하기도 하지
What a good boy, you are.
어쩜 이렇게 착할까!
Hey, Bones. Are you hungry?
'본즈'
배고프니?
Come on, check that out.
There you go.
어서 먹어
-Yes, Samuel?
-Hello? Mikaela?
- 샘이구나
- 미카엘라
l can't believe you're gonna stand me up
on our first web chat date.
첫 메신저 데이트에
바람 맞히다니
-Something just happened to me, okay?
-What, you finally hit puberty?
- 일이 있었어
- 사춘기라도 왔니?
No, no, no. Stop laughing.
This is serious. Okay.
농담 아냐
Remember l was telling you
about my great-great-grandfather,
아치발드 윗위키 고조부님
Archibald Witwicky? Remember?
얘기 기억해?
Watch it, watch it, watch... No!
Okay, remember how l was telling you...
조심해요!
내가 말했었지
Okay. Can you stop?
Watch the foot! Watch your foot!
발 조심해!
발!
Mikaela, okay,
my great-great-grandfather
went on this Arctic mission, right?
고조할아버지가
북극탐사 하시다가
And he saw Megatron.
Megatron zapped him,
'메가트론' 때문에
보시게 된
and he started seeing
these crazy symbols. Okay.
Well, now l'm seeing them, too.
Excuse me.
기호가 나도 보여
l just read a 903-page astronomy book
in 32.6 seconds.
32.6초 만에 천문학 책
903페이지를 읽었고
l had a meltdown
in the middle of my class.
l am seeing symbols ever since l...
그때 후로
기호가 보여서...
-Since what?
-Ever since l touched the Cube splinter.
- 그때라니?
- 큐브 조각 만진 후
-Do you have it?
-Yeah, l have it.
- 갖고 있지?
- 응
-lt's in the shop safe. lt's fine.
-Mikaela, do not touch it, okay?
- 가게 금고에 있어
- 절대로 만지지 마
-Don't touch it.
-l'm not gonna touch it.
안 만질게
Sam, it's fine. lt's locked away.
잠겨 있고 아무도
거깄는 거 몰라
-No one knows where it is.
-l do!
난 알지
You're hot, but you ain't too bright.
외모는 되는데
좀 맹하군
There we go. Yeah, that'll work.
어디...
그렇지, 이제 되겠다
Damn it! Son of a bitch!
망할!
What are you looking at, slobber puss?
뭘 보냐, 침흘리개야?
What the... This place is
a freaking house of horrors!
이건 또...?
어디 살벌해서 살겠나!
Pain... lt hurts...
아파라
Hold on.
잠깐
Right to five, then...
5 다음엔 뭐시냐...
ls that the best you got, huh?
ls that the best you can do?
겨우 그거냐?
그거밖엔 안 돼?
What are you doing here,
you little freak?
여기서 뭐 해
이 괴물아?!
That's my eye, you crazy bitch!
내 눈!
이 망할 계집!
-You gonna talk now?
-l seek knowledge from the Cube.
- 이제 실토할래?
- 큐브 정보를 캐란
-The Fallen demands me!
-What knowledge?
- '폴른' 님 명령이야!
- 무슨 정보?
You got the shard, l need the shard.
Give me the shard. l need the shard.
그 조각
네가 가진 조각
They're gonna whack me!
l'm gonna be dead without that shard!
못 가져가면 죽음이야
Easy, warrior goddess,
l'm just a little salvage-scrap drone!
진정해라, 여전사야
난 고철덩어리일 뿐이야!
-And l'm your worst nightmare.
-Hey, hey, hey!
이 안에 가만있어!
-What the hell was that?
-l'll tell you later,
- 뭐였어?
- 도청될까 봐 말 못해
just not on an open phone line, okay?
l'm gonna get on a plane right now
이따 비행기로 갈게
and l'll be there later this afternoon.
Just be careful, Sam.
And have any strangers given you
anything suspicious to carry on today?
낯선 사람이 수상한 물건을
맡겼습니까?
Yeah, a live bomb!
네, 폭탄이오!
-No.
-Good.
- 아뇨
- 좋아요
'오토봇'의
도움 요청입니다!
Major, incoming SOS from Autobots!
Multiple Decepticon contacts in motion.
Vicinity, eastern United States, sir!
'디셉티콘'의 움직임이
동부에서 포착됐답니다!
-As in how many?
-Unclear, sir.
- 얼마나 되나?
- 모르겠습니다
그럼 알아보게
Well, get clear.
'오토봇'이 두 팀으로 나눠
출동했습니다
The Autobots are on the move,
splitting into two teams, sir.
뉴욕과 필라델피아로
갑니다
They're not answering our calls
and they're heading to
New York and Philadelphia.
무기 장착해
20분 후 이륙한다!
All right, full weapons deployment.
Wheels up in 20 minutes!
Move it!
서둘러!
가자!
Let's go!
Flight 57, welcome to Philadelphia.
57기, 필라델피아에
도착했습니다
Alicia, mi amor, can l interest you
in an 1 8-inch Zookeeper's special?
앨리스, 18인치짜리
'동물의 왕국' 피자 먹을래?
각종 고기에 치즈까지
Extra-large, triple cheese,
with every known animal as a topping.
고기맛 실컷 봐 봐
Basically, l've got,
like, 1 8 inches of meat.
너 채식주의자니?
나도
Unless you're vegetarian.
All right. lt's cool. l am, too.
- 샘 있니?
- 죽었을걸, 볼래?
-Sam home?
-Sam? l think he died,
but why don't we check?
-Here we are.
-Hey!
어디 보자
어떤 노래가 머릿속에
맴돈 적 있어?
You ever have a song stuck
in your head? lt's like
좋지도 않은데
the worst song ever,
but you can't help to whistle it or sing it
계속 반복하고 반복하고
'cause it, like, repeats itself, repeats
itself, repeats itself, repeats itself?
Kitten calendar,
kitten calendar, kitten calendar,
야옹이 달력...
야, 너 뭐냐?
-kitten calendar...
-Dude, what the eff?
l know you're freaking out.
Don't freak out. Don't freak out.
걱정 마
Easy fix. Puzzle code in my head.
이상한 암호가
떠올라서 그래
다 쓰니깐
속 시원하다
Now it's on the walls.
Everything is good.
This is the part that...
너 뭐랬지?
Okay, what were you saying?
Alice, l'm horrified you had to see this.
Let's go.
험한 꼴 보지 말고
나가자
너나 나가
Get out.
그냥 있으면 안 될까?
Wait, wait, wait!
Can l just sit and watch?
l'll... l'll eat my pizza quietly.
조용히 피자나 먹을게
Sam, l knew there was
something special about you.
샘, 넌 특별한 데가
있더라
Really?
And l know you know what happens
속사정을 잘 알면
when two people in the know
get together.
속궁합도 잘 맞지
They're genuinely amazing in bed.
아주 환상적일 거야
침대에서...
Thank you.
고맙습니다
All right, listen, hold on! Boundaries.
거기까지, 그만 해
-Flag on the play. Okay. l'm very ticklish.
-We have needs, Sam. Relax.
- 이건 아니라고 봐
- 욕망을 발산해보자
Jeez!
맙소사!
What about this economy?
lt's crazy, isn't it?
요즘 경제가
말이 아니지?
-You are very aggressive.
-Just relax.
- 너무 무섭게 덤빈다
- 긴장 풀어
You want some turkey meatloaf?
간식 먹을래?
Sam?
샘?
-Mikaela!
-ls that your girlfriend?
- 미카엘라?
- 네 여자친구?
Ex.
이젠 아냐
Mikaela! Wait!
미카엘라?
기다려!
l can explain...
내가 다 설명...
Sam, your bed buddy, Alice...
네 침실 친구
앨리스가...
All right, come on.
-She's coming!
-She's an alien robot! You gotta move.
- 온다!
- 외계 로봇이야!
-ls this real?
-Just run!
- 진짜?
- 뛰어!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! l can't believe
l almost had sex with her in my dream!
나 꿈에서 쟤랑
할 뻔했단 말이야!
l can tell
that you really missed me a lot, Sam!
나 무지
보고 싶었겠네
-Look, it's not my fault, okay?
-lt's not your fault?
나도 엄연히 당한 거야
Listen! Listen, l'm a victim!
-You were a victim? Of what?
-Yeah.
당해?
-Of what, a little 80-pound girl?
-Of... Of molestation.
쬐끄만 여자애한테?
lt was like getting humped
in the neck by a mountain ox!
기운도 황소보다 세
You didn't have to put your tongue
in her mouth!
키스도 진하더라
-l didn't! Look!
-You did!
무슨!
You ever had your stomach tongued by
a mountain ox with a five-foot tongue?
황소가 혀를
날름대는데 좋겠냐?
lt's not fun for me, okay, Mikaela?
And it smelled like... Like diesel!
난 안 좋거든
게다가 어찌나
-Like a diesel-y tinge to it!
-You're such a little girl!
- 기름냄새가 나는지!
- 언제 철들래!
We're gonna have
1 0 seconds of silence right now.
우리 10초 동안
조용히 있자
l'm not talking to you for 1 0 seconds.
You can't give me the silent treatment!
You know what?
억울한 척하지 마
l'm not talking to you for 1 0 seconds.
You have three seconds left.
3초 남았어
You know what?
You can give me the silent treatment
너나 입 다물어
all you want,
but you can't keep me from talking.
난 할 말 할래
-What were you gonna say?
-l hope you had a lot of fun,
- 무슨 말?
- 재미 좀 봤니?
because this, this is over.
이제 우린 끝이야
She violated your orifice
with her nasty alien probe?
그 더러운 촉수에
알을 담아선
She did it? She went in there?
All her little embryo alien babies
네 입속에 넣었으니까
are gestating and hatching inside of you.
They're growing right now, probably!
곧 뱃속에서 부화할 거야
You need to vomit it right now.
Yak it! Yak it right now!
다 토해내, 어서!
Who are you?
얜 또 누구야?
l'm Leonardo Ponce De Leon Spitz.
Okay? l'm the key to this.
레오 스피츠, 외계 로봇들이
내 사이트를 노리지
The aliens,
they want me 'cause of my site.
Whoa, guys, right there!
피해!
Run!
뛰어!
Mikaela!
미카엘라!
Come on! We gotta move!
피해야 돼
lt's a bomb!
폭탄이다!
You've got to get that box!
상자 들어!
-This way.
-What? Hey! Let me out, let me out!
- 이쪽이야
- 날 내보내줘!
Oh, my God, you know how to
hot-wire a car? That's so hot!
그런 것도 해?
멋진걸
Drive, drive, drive!
She's right there! She's right there!
밟아, 저깄어!
Come on, come on, come on.
제발, 제발...
Go! Go! Go! Back up the car!
가, 후진해!
Now!
빨리 후진해!
Tongue!
혀, 혀, 혀!
Oh, my God!
잡혔어!
Kiss this, bitch!
쟤하고나 뽀뽀해라!
Drive, drive, drive.
빨리, 빨리, 빨리!
Okay, so what else
don't l know, all right?
내가 외계 로봇에 대해
Since you guys forgot to mention
some minor details.
모르는 게 있나 봐?
That thing you saw back there,
that was the little baby...
아까 그건 약과야
-Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
-Sam!
- 난 몰라!
- 샘!
Sam!
-Sam!
-Hold on!
샘!
-Pull me up!
-Hold on!
올려줘!
Sam, get back in!
샘, 빨리 타!
l don't want to die!
We're gonna die! Oh, my God!
나 죽기 싫어!
하느님, 나 죽어요!
Jesus! Jesus!
맙소사!
Come here, boy.
이리 오거라
Closer.
더 가까이
-Oh, my God.
-Okay.
You remember me, don't you?
날 기억하겠지?
l did what you said, okay?
Just don't hurt us.
시키는 대로 했으니까
우릴 놔둬
Shut up!
닥쳐라!
Sam!
Yeah! Yes, yes.
그렇지
lt feels good to grab your flesh!
널 잡고 있으니
좋구나!
l am going to kill you slowly, painfully,
널 죽일 것이다
서서히 고통스럽게!
but first, we have
some delicate work to do.
허나 먼저
같이 해야 할 일이 있다
How l could snap your limbs off!
Doctor, examine this alien specimen.
'닥터', 이 외계인을
검사하라
l'll scan you.
Let's take a look at your face.
l'm the doctor. The odd job. lnformation!
난 '닥터'다
정보를 넘겨라!
Yeah!
Beseeching my shard!
Easy or tough way?
말로 할 때 듣지?
-There they are.
-That's what l'm seeing in my head.
- 거기 있구나
- 맴돌던 기호인데...
These symbols can lead us
to the Energon source.
이 기호가 에너지 원천으로
안내할 것이다
We must have the brain on the table!
이제 뇌를 꺼내봐야지
-Chop, chop!
-Brain?
- 빨리, 빨리!
- 뇌?
What does he mean by my brain?
뇌라니?
Well, you have something on your mind,
something l need.
넌 내가 원하는 걸
머릿속에 담고 있잖아
Hold on. l know you're pissed.
l know you're pissed
화났구나
because l tried to kill you
and it's completely understandable.
누가 날 죽이려 했다면
lf somebody tried to kill me,
l'd be upset, too.
나도 화날 거야
l think that we have an opportunity here
우리 이 기회에
to start anew
and develop our relationship
우리 관계를
새로 시작해보자
and see where it leads us, okay?
So, you just call Doctor lnspector off
and let's just talk for five seconds!
'닥터'는 손떼라 그러고
5초만 얘기하자!
Wait, wait, wait!
-Come on! Go, go!
-Sam!
- 뛰어, 어서!
- 샘!
Go, go, go!
뛰어!
Sam!
샘!
Run!
뛰어!
Go, go, go, go!
빨리 가!
Here he comes!
녀석이 와요!
숨어라, 샘!
Hide, Sam!
약골!
Weak!
하잘것없는 쓰레기!
Puny! Waste of metal!
고철덩이!
Junkyard crap!
'디셉티콘'!
Decepticons!
이리 와, 꼬마야
Come here, boy.
There is another source of
Energon hidden on this planet.
지구에 에너지 원천이
또 있다
The boy could lead us to it.
저 꼬마를 따라가라!
Optimus!
'옵티머스'!
ls the future of our race not worth
a single human life?
우리 종족의 미래가
인간 하나보다 못한가?
-Up! Get up!
-You'll never stop at one!
- 일어나요!
- 한 명 죽이는 걸로 끝낼 리 없지
내가 상대해주겠다!
l'll take you all on!
내 팔!!
이런 깡통 조각!
Piece of tin!
샘, 어딨느냐?
Sam! Where are you?
안 돼!
No!
나약하기 짝이 없군!
You're so weak!
The last Prime is dead!
마지막 '프라임'이
죽었다
샘, 뛰어라
Sam, run. Run.
'오토봇'들아, 공격해!
Autobots, attack!
'범블비', 데리고 가!
Bumblebee, get them out of here!
레녹스 소령이다
This is Lennox.
- 일이 잘 처리됐군
- 꼬마를 놓쳤습니다
-That went well.
-We've lost the boy, Master.
'오토봇'들은
어딘가 숨었구요
The Autobots
must be shielding their signals.
벌레 한 마리도
감당 못하다니!
l can't even rely on you
to swat a simple insect?
- 벌레 소굴인걸요
- 시끄럽다!
-One insect among seven billion!
-Shut up!
어딘가 있겠죠
He could be anywhere.
인간들을 이용해서
놈을 찾아라!
Then we will force them
to find him for us!
세상에 우리 존재를
알릴 때가 됐다
lt's time for the world
to know of our presence.
더는 인정사정
봐줄 거 없다!
No more disguises. No mercy!
사부님이 오실 때가
된 것이다
The time has come
for my master's arrival.
'디셉티콘', 출동하라
때가 왔다
Decepticons, mobilize. lt is time.
불어 너무 재밌다
Speaking French is so exciting!
어머, 누구지?
Oh, God, who is this?
여보세요?
아니, 봉쥬르!
Hello? l mean, bonsoir!
- 네? 누구세요?
- 꼬마는 어딨나?
-What? Who is this?
-Where is the boy?
웬일이니!
목소리 깔아도 안 멋있거든
For Pete's sakes. l'm not impressed
with your perverted mouth-breathing.
뉴욕 시
깜짝이야!
Jeez!
분위기 깨긴
좋은 말 할 때 가쇼
You are invading my space.
l'm gonna have to drop you.
Would you get out of here?
저런 놈들
딱 질색이야
l didn't come all the way across
the ocean to eat a plate of snails.
이국적이야
l want to try new things.
완전 거위 응가네
Looks like Canadian goose poop.
맛없어
lt's nasty.
제2 함대, 북대서양
복수는 나의 것이다
Revenge is mine.
Yeah!
미 국방성: 워싱턴
비행기가 아니었고...
...definitely not a plane...
항공모함은 그냥
침몰한 게 아니오
Look, carriers don't just sink.
...테러인 것 같습니다
...a horrible accident or a terrorist
attack or worse...
방위사령부
분석결과
Negative. NORAD confirmed,
미사일은 대기권 밖에서 시속
5만6천 킬로로 투하된 겁니다
projectile came from beyond our
atmosphere, inbound at 30,000 knots.
지구인들은 들어라
Citizens of the human hive,
너희 지도자들은
진실을 숨기고 있다
your leaders have withheld the truth.
이 우주엔 너희만
사는 게 아니다
You are not alone in this universe.
우리도 너희들 속에서
숨어 살았지만
We have lived among you, hidden,
이젠 아니다
but no more.
봤다시피
너희 도시를 날릴 수도 있으니
As you've seen,
we can destroy your cities at will,
그 꼬마를 넘겨라
unless you turn over this boy.
반항한다면 보란듯이
전 세계를 파괴해주겠다
lf you resist us, we will destroy
the world as you know it.
독일정부에 따르면
What we're hearing
from the German government
위성 해킹을 한 거라고 합니다
is that the worId broadcast
was a satellite hacking.
군에선 911사태 이후
The military has just told us they have
assumed Condition Delta,
트랜스포머 작전팀: 뉴저지
최고 비상령을 내렸습니다
which is the highest level
we have been at since 9/1 1 .
오바마 대통령은
지하로 대피하며
President Obama
is being flown to a bunker
somewhere in the middle
of the United States
전 세계적인 공격에
당황하고 있습니다
in the face of the worst simultaneous
attacks ever around the globe.
항공모함 '루즈벨트'호가
동부해안에서 침몰했습니다
The aircraft carrier USS Roosevelt goes
down off the East Coast, all hands lost.
현재 사상자는 약 7천명이나
WorIdwide casualties
are in the neighborhood of 7,000,
더 늘어날 걸로 보입니다
but that number could climb.
현 시점에 궁금한 건
누가 왜 그랬냐는 겁니다
lt's still too early to tell.
What we need to ask now is,
"Who and why?"
The FBl is still trying to locate
the boy, Sam Witwicky.
FBl에선 샘 윗위키의
행방을 찾고 있는데요
그에게 정보가
있을 걸로 보입니다
We believe they have information
about the attacks.
FBl, ClA, 인터폴이 협력해
The FBl, ClA and lnterpol
수사를 벌이려고 합니다
are all seeking the cooperation
of worIdwide law enforcement.
이것 좀 들어봐
You need to listen to this, man.
You gotta check this out.
-They have a traffic-camera spotting...
-They have a picture of me, man.
내 사진까지
우린 죽었다!
FBl, ClA에서 쫓고 있어!
We're dead, bro.
FBl, ClA, we are wanted fugitives now!
정신 똑바로 차려
l just need you to focus
-for one minute, man.
-Just stop.
사태가 장난 아니게 커졌어
This thing has blown up
to a whole other level, all right?
줘봐
위치추적 당할라
You know what? Give me this thing.
They can track us.
-Do you see this?
-What?
They can track us?
Like, satellite track us?
위치추적?
위성추적처럼?
나 사실 끌려온 거야
Okay, l'm not even with you guys!
엄밀히 인질이라고
Technically, l'm like a hostage.
This is kidnapping...
야, 레오!
-Enough is...
-Yo, Leo!
간 떨어질 뻔했잖아
This thing's gonna
give me a heart attack, l swear.
- 쫄긴!
- 날 태우고 왔잖아
-That's 'cause you is a wuss.
-You guys forced me into that car, right?
벌벌 떨긴
l think he's scared.
저 찌질이를 어째?
Hey, Mudflap, what are we gonna do
with this shrimp taco?
트렁크에
처박아두자
Let's pop a cap in his ass,
throw him in the trunk
and then nobody gonna know nothing,
know what l mean?
- 니 트렁크에나 넣어둬
- 야, 범퍼카들아
-Not in my trunk.
-Yo, bumper cars? l'm hearing you.
안됐지만 다 들었거든?
Okay? l'm right here and l can hear you!
트렁크 같은 소리하네
No one's popping any caps
in any asses, okay?
피곤하니까 건들지 마
l've had a hell of a day!
머리나 좀 자르지?
Why don't you get a haircut
with your bitch ass?
또 징징대 봐
Go whine to your boyfriend!
샘, 경찰한테
난 이 일하곤
Listen, Sam, l know what l'm gonna do,
man. Look, l'm just going to go
to the authorities and tell them the truth.
상관없다고 할래
Like, l had nothing to do with this.
초대박을 원해?
-So, l'm not an accomplice.
-Hey, you wanted this, right?
이게 그거야
완전 대박이라고
You wanted the real deal?
Well, that's what this is.
Wake up! You're in the middle of it!
그래도 갈 거면 가
You want to run? Go ahead!
No one's stopping you.
투덜대지 말고!
Stop complaining.
이건 무슨 뜻이지?
What is the meaning of this?
감히 날 겨눠?!
You dare point a gun at me?
한번 해 볼테냐?!
아작을 내주마!
You want a piece of me?
l will tear you apart!
당장 무기를 버려라!
Drop your weapons! Drop your weapons!
- 당장 버려요!
- 그쪽 먼저!
-Tell them to lower their weapons!
-Tell them first.
먼저 하래도
Tell them to lower their weapons.
Major, there's nothing l can do.
Talk to him.
트랜스포머 작전팀은
해체됐네
Your NEST team is deactivated, Major.
'디셉티콘'에 맞서지 말고
돌아가게
You are to cease
anti-Decepticon operations
and return to Diego Garcia
pending further orders.
저흰 합참의장님
명령에 따릅니다
No, we take our orders directly
from Chairman Morshower, sir.
합참의장을 떠나서
Well, l'll see your Chairman
of the Joint Chiefs of Staff
대통령께서
내게 일임하셨네
and l will raise you
a President of the United States.
l have operational command now.
외계 로봇 집안 싸움으로
An alien blood feud
has been brought to our shores
군인들이 희생되다니
for which our soldiers
are paying the price.
비밀이 드러난 이상
The secret is out!
군사전략을 토대로
This is our war now and we will win it
as we always have,
맞서 싸워 이길 걸세
with a coordinated military strategy.
분위기 파악 못하네
This fool is terribly misinformed.
상대도 안 될걸요
You're gonna need every asset
that you've got.
가능한 한 타협적으로
해결할 걸세
What we need is to draw up battle plans
while we explore
every possible diplomatic solution.
꼬마를 넘기시게요?
Like what, handing over the kid?
그것도 가능하지
All options are being considered.
'디셉티콘'이 뭘 찾든
이건 시작일 뿐입니다
Whatever the Decepticons are after,
this is just the start.
- 그들에게 타협은 없죠
- 빠지라니까!
-There is no negotiating with them.
-l'm ordering you to stand down.
이건 떼버리고
기지로 돌아가게
You won't be needing this anymore.
Get your assets back to base!
저 고물 깡통도
가지고 가
And take that pile of scrap metal back
to Diego Garcia.
가지
Let's go!
주는 거 없이 싫은데요
밥맛이에요
l really don't like that dude.
He's an asshole.
'오토봇'들은
이송준비하라
Autobots, report to hangar for transport.
- '아이언하이드', 지구를 떠야겠어
- 그건 '옵티머스' 님 뜻이 아냐
-lronhide, we should leave this planet.
-That's not what Optimus would want.
너도 어쩔 수 없었어
There's nothing
that you could have done.
- 괜찮아?
- 응
-You okay?
-Yeah.
'범블비'
날 미워해도 이해해
Bee, if you hate me, l understand.
내가 잘못했어
미안해
l messed up. l'm sorry.
넌 내가 가장
아끼는 사람이다
Young fella, you are the person
l care about most in my life.
날 필요로 한다면
곁에 있을게
lf there's anything you need,
l won't be far away.
나 때문에 죽었어
날 보호하려다 죽은 거야
He's dead because of me. He came
here to protect me and he's dead.
세상엔 바꿀 수
없는 게 있어
There's some things
you just can't change.
그분의 희생은 헛되지 않아
할렐루야!
So, his sacrifice for us would
not have been in vain. Hallelujah!
내가 가야겠어
l'm gonna make it right.
l'm going to turn myself in.
우린 뭉쳐야 돼
We... We've got to stick together.
- 가면 안 돼
- 가야 돼
-You're not going to do that.
-Yes, l am.
우리가 애써온 게
하루아침에 날아가게 됐어
Everything we worked for
will be wiped out in one day!
너희 둘!
-You two...
-Huh?
상형문자 알아?
Hey, you know the glyphs?
이 기호가 자꾸 떠올라
These? The symbols that have been
rattling around in my head?
오래된 건데
사이버트론 언어 같아
That's old school, yo.
That's, like... That's Cybertronian.
중요한 거 같은데
That's some serious stuff, right there.
메시지거나 지도일 거야
They gotta mean something,
like a message or like a map.
에너지 원천 약도!
Like a map to an Energon source!
- 읽을 수 있어?
- 읽어? 저기...
-Can you read this?
-Read?
우린 까막눈이라
No. We don't really do much reading.
Not so much.
그럼 읽을 사람을
찾자
lf you can't read it,
we gotta find somebody who can.
누가 슬쩍 돌아왔네
Look who came sashaying back!
머리가 산발이야
Hair growing like a Chia Pet.
Look at him.
내가 좀 쫄았었어
l had a bit
of a mild panic attack earlier, right?
겁쟁이니까
사실 쫄 만도 했지, 뭐
That's 'cause you're a pussy.
l think l'm allowed that,
considering what l've been through.
- 나 우릴 도와줄 사람을 알아
- 누군데?
l heard you have a problem.
-l think l know someone who can help.
-Who?
로보워리어!
Robo-Warrior.
로보워리어 자식은
This guy, Robo-Warrior,
외계 로봇 통이야
everything about anything alien,
he's supposed to know.
걔 사이트
해킹하다가
One time we revenge-hacked his site
그 외계 그림
같은 것도 봤어
and maybe l saw some
of your alien drawings or whatever.
여기야
This is it. Yep.
가게가
위장하기엔 최고지
Deli. Good front!
기다려
분위기 보고 올게
All right, wait here.
l'll give you the go/no go. All right?
42번 손님
Number 42, we got your kishka, knish,
주문하신
각종 음식 나왔습니다
kasha-varnishka
and kreplach combo right here.
현찰만 받아요
다음?
Cash only. Who's next?
연어는 소금물에
담갔다 훈제하래도
l told you to cure the lox in the brine
and then smoke it.
엄마, 그러다
나 손 베면?
Ma, you want me
to cut my hand off, or what?
못쓰게 됐잖아
You... You ruined
a beautiful piece of fish, you retard!
나 사시미 잘 떠
l'm like a ninja with a blade.
lt's an art form.
시끄러
Give me your money. Get out of here!
샐, 어딜 만지려고!
번호표 뽑아라
Hey, Sal! Watch your reach, huh?
Take a number, young man.
로보워리어
Robo-Warrior.
- 아세요?
- 처음 듣는데
-Know him?
-l never heard of him.
'초대박.com'은요?
You never heard of
TheRealEffingDeal.com?
보안이 애들 장난수준인
You must be talking about that
amateur-hour blog operation
- 유치찬란 블로그!
- 로보워리어...
-with Game Boy-level security.
-Robo-Warrior.
저자야!
바로 저 사람이라고
lt's him! lt's him!
That's the guy right there! That's him!
설마...
No.
- 말문이 다 막히네
- 장사 안 합니다
-You got to be kidding me.
-All right, meat store's closed!
나가세요!
어서요!
-Everybody out! Out, right now!
-When he says to go,
꾸물대지 말고요
-you go.
-That means you, lady, right now.
- 너 알아?
- 옛날 친구야
-Wait a minute. You know this guy?
-We're old friends.
친구?
너 때문에 '섹터7'이 아작났어
Old friends? You're the case
that shut down Sector Seven,
개 쫓기듯 쫓겨났지
got the kibosh, disbanded.
퇴직금 한 푼 못 받고
옷 벗었다고
No more security clearance,
no retirement, no nothing.
다 너 때문이야!
All 'cause of you
and your little criminal girlfriend.
- 싹수 노란 여자친구 많이 컸네
- 이 웬수야! 송어 어쨌어?
-Look at her now, so mature.
-Moron! Where's the whitefish?
그걸로 나 건들지 마!
Hey! Don't touch me with the pig.
- 야콥!
- 왜요?
-Yakov!
-What?
농땡이 치면
보너스 없어!
You don't get
Christmas bonuses standing around!
이빨 새로
해 넣겠다며?
You want those new teeth
you saw on SkyMall?
- 어느 세월에!
- 빨리 거들어
-lt's my dream.
-Help her out.
엄마랑 살아요?
You live with your mama?
엄마가 나한테 얹혀살지
No, my mama lives with me.
lt's a big difference.
너 뉴스에 도배됐던데
They got your face all over the news,
alien boy.
-Yeah, l know.
-And NBE One's still kicking, huh?
'메가트론'이 살아있어?
어떻게 그런 일이?
대답하지 마
How did that happen? Don't answer.
난 끼어들기 싫으니
l don't know what you're hiding,
but l don't want anything to do with it.
나 못 본 걸로 해라
그냥 사라져줘
So, good-bye. You never saw me.
l got bagels to schmear. Vanish.
잠깐만요
저 좀 도와줘요
Can you give me five seconds?
Look, hold on, l need your help.
정말?
널 도와달라고?
Really? You need my help?
저 미칠 것만 같아요
l need...
Look, l am slowly losing my mind.
이상한 로봇이
Okay, l had a little crab-bot,
내 머리를 찌르자
plunged a device deep into
the soft tissues of my brain
외계기호가 영화처럼
나타났어요
and started projecting little alien
symbols like a freaking home movie!
또 쫓기고 있는데
어떻게 안 돼요?
And on top of that, l'm a wanted fugitive.
So, you think you got it rough?
뇌에서 영상을
뽑아내?
You said it projected images
off your brain?
-Right.
-Meat locker, now!
냉장실로, 빨리!
돼지 시체다
Dead pigs.
이건
일급기밀이니깐
What you're about to see is top secret.
울 엄마한텐
말하지 마
Do not tell my mother.
신종독감 걸릴라
-Swine flu. Not good.
-Now you know.
앞으로 돼지고기 먹을 땐
걔들의 슬픈 사연도
Next time you eat a goat or a pig,
there's a story behind it.
생각해줘
Sad little story.
An entire city flat.
How do you explain that?
외계 로봇을
믿으세요?
Are you saying you believe
in aliens now?
이거 서류 천지군
기호가 어디 있을 텐데
Okay, files, files.
We're talking about symbols.
방사능이 있으니
만지지 마
Hey, still radioactive. Hands off.
좋았어, 큐브가이
Okay, Cube-brain.
이런 기호를 본 거야?
Any of these look
like the symbols you saw?
어디서 났어요?
Where'd you get these?
잘리기 전에
기밀문서를 슬쩍 했지
Before l got fired,
l poached S-7's crown jewel,
75년간의 외계 로봇 연구 끝에
알아낸 진실은 이거야
over 75 years of alien research,
which points to one inescapable fact.
트랜스포머들은 여기에
오래 전부터 살았어
The Transformers,
they've been here a long, long time.
어떻게 아냐고?
How do l know?
이 알 수 없는 표시가
Archeologists found
these unexplained markings
전 세계
고대유적에서 발견됐어
in ancient ruins all over the world.
중국, 이집트, 그리스
China. Egypt. Greece.
1932년에 찍은 건데
Shot in 1 932.
이런 기호를 본 거지?
These the symbols
you're seeing in your head?
바로 이런 거?
-Yeah.
-Same ones over here, right?
그럼 어떻게 다
같은 걸 그렸을까?
So, tell me, how did they end up
all drawing the same things?
외계 로봇 짓이지
아직도 여기서 살걸
Aliens. And l think some of them stayed.
이걸 봐
프로젝트 '블랙 나이프'!
Check this out. Project Black Knife.
위장한 로봇들이...
숨어 있는 거지
Robots in disguise,
hiding here all along.
전국에 걸쳐
방사능 검출기에 포착됐어
We detected radioactive signatures
all across the country.
'섹터7'에선 간곡히
조사를 부탁했지만
l pleaded on my knees with S-7
to investigate it,
수치가 약하단
말뿐이더군
but they said the readings
were infinitesimal,
나더러 오버한다고
that l was obsessed.
내가 오버하는 거 같아?
Me. Can you imagine that?
'메가트론'은 에너지
원천이 또 있대요
Yeah. Megatron said that there
was another Energon source here.
지구에 다른 원천이?
-On Earth. Another source?
-On Earth.
이 기호가
안내할 거라고
Okay? And that these symbols,
maps in my head, would lead him there.
'오토봇'에게
물어봤어?
You talk to your Autobot friends
about this?
아뇨
No, no, no, the source is before them.
에너지 원천은
그들보다 먼저 얘긴걸요
Whatever the Energon source is,
it predates them.
lt's before them.
- 먼저 생긴거군
- 그렇죠
-So, it comes before them.
-Correct.
그럼 큰일이네
'디셉티콘'을 만나보든가
Well, then we're porked,
unless we can talk to a Decepticon.
난 썩 친하질 않아서
l mean,
l'm not on speaking terms with them.
난 좀 친해요
Actually, l am.
내보내줘!
Let me out!
영 내키진 않네
-This is going to be a little bit sad.
-Open it.
내가 너희들
다 이를 거야!
l will have so many Decepticons
on your butt!
얌전히 굴어!
Hey, behave!
- 저게 '디셉티콘'?
- 응
-What is it, a Decepticon?
-Yeah.
- 훈련시키게?
- 해보려고
-And you're training him?
-l'm trying to.
난 외계 로봇 찾느라
지구를 이 잡듯 뒤졌는데
l spent my whole adult life combing
the planet for aliens,
넌 치와와처럼
데리고 다니다니
and you're carrying around one
in your purse like a little Chihuahua.
한판 붙어볼래
곱슬아?
Do you want a throwdown,
you pubic 'fro-head?
눈 지진 건
미안한데
l'm sorry.
l'm so sorry about your eye, you know,
말 잘 들으면
한쪽 눈은 놔둘게
but, if you're a good boy,
then l'm not gonna torch your other eye.
알았지?
절대 안 지져
Okay? l'm not gonna torch it.
이 기호들이
뭔지나 말해주라
Just tell me
what these symbols are, please.
All right.
좋아
나 그거 알아
'프라임'들 언어지
l know that.
That's the language of the Primes.
난 못 읽지만
이분들은...
l don't read it, but these guys...
이분들 사진
어디서 났어?
Where the frick did you find photos
of these guys?
- '이분들'?
- 선구자들이셔
-ls this they?
-Yeah. Seekers, pal. Oldest of the old.
오래 전에 오셔서
수천 년 동안 뭔가 찾고 계셔
They've been here thousands of years,
looking for something. l don't know what.
이 기호를
풀 수 있을걸
Nobody tells me nothing, but they'll
translate those symbols for you.
- 나 그분들 있는 델 알아
- 짚어봐
-And l know where to find them.
-Show us.
Yeah.
워싱턴이
제일 가깝군
The closest one's in Washington.
스미소니안 항공우주 박물관!
꿈의 땅이지
Smithsonian Air and Space Museum.
Land of dreams in there.
내 꿈은
우주비행사였거든
All l ever wanted to be was an astronaut.
- 잡아봐
- 뭐예요?
-Hold those.
-What is that?
섹터7
What? l wear them when l'm in a funk.
겁날 땐 이걸 입어
유명한 야구선수도
많이들 그런대
So does Giambi, Jeter.
lt's a baseball thing. Okay.
시계 맞추고
정신 바짝 차리고
Watches synchronized,
sharp mind and empty bladder.
붙잡혀도
난 불지 마
You get caught, demand an attorney
and don't ever say my name.
이거 하나씩 먹어
Okay, take one of these pills.
Slip it under your tongue.
고농축 약물인데
이거 한 알이면
lt's the high-concentrate polymer
they put in Oreo cookies.
거짓말탐지기도 무사통과야
Tricks the polygraph every time.
그럼 시작하자
Okay. Now, let's get this show
on the road.
난 못해
No, listen, l can't do this.
난 외계 로봇
사냥꾼 아냐!
l'm not some alien bounty hunter, guys.
l'm not gonna do this.
- 총 맞아 죽긴 싫어!
- 꼬마야, 꼬마야
-Guards have guns. l don't want to die.
-Kid, kid, kid.
임무를 더럽히면
내 손에 죽는다
You compromise this mission,
you are dead to me.
날 보고 똥꼬에 힘줘
Now look into my eyes
and tighten up that sphincter.
박물관을
닫겠습니다
The museum is now closing.
이를 어째
휴지가 없잖아!
Yo, baba! Bad news, bro!
Ran out of toilet paper!
휴지 한 뭉텅이만 줘요
You got any out here?
Please tell me you do.
들어가세요
곧 문 닫습니다!
Sir! l suggest you get in there.
The museum is closed!
알지만
한참 힘주다가
Listen, man, l understand that,
but as you can see, this is important.
끊을 순 없잖아요
All right? Thumper dumper.
l got to go. All right.
애들 앞에서
옷을 벗다뇨
Sir, you are a grown,
naked man around children.
- 옷 입고 나가세요
- 가긴 어딜 가요
-Pull your pants up and exit the building.
-l'm not going anywhere.
- 휴지는요?
- 아실 만한 분이
-You got that paper, right, sir?
-You should be embarrassed.
박물관에서 뭡니까!
This is a family museum, sir.
넌 거기 왜 누웠냐?
What is going on here?
이걸로 거시기 맞았다고
고자 되진 않겠죠?
How many times can you get tased
in the nuts before you can't have kids?
왜 이래
아마추어 같이!
You are an amateur, man,
a rank amateur.
경비 5명 해치웠어
We just downed five guards.
Five guards.
어서 챙겨서 가자
-Get your stuff and get out of here.
-Give me a second here.
난 검출기 꺼낼게
l got to get the tracker, all right.
말 잘 들어
-Be good.
-l'm claustrophobic.
따라가 봐
뭔가 찾아낼 거야
Look, look. Follow him. Follow him.
He knows where he's going.
-He knows something.
-What?
분명 뭔가 안다고
He knows something.
확실한 거야?
You got what l got?
- 네
- '블랙버드'
-Yeah.
-Blackbird.
이분이야
There he is.
이분이야말로 전설이지
로봇계의 거성이랄까!
This guy's a legend,
like the Chairman of the Board!
야, 신입, 조각 들어 봐
마법이 일어나나 보자
Yo, freshman, point the shard
and watch the magic happen.
'디셉티콘'이야!
Shit. lt's a Decepticon!
'디셉티콘'?
-Decepticon?
'미그'기 뒤에 숨어!
Behind the MiG now!
뭐 이런 고약한 동네가
다 있나?!
What sort of hideous
mausoleum is this?
여봐라, 대답하라!
Answer me, pawns and knaves!
정체를 밝히지 않으면
무서운 맛을 보리라!
Show yourselves
or suffer my infinite wrath!
이 하찮은
인간 생물들아!
You little spinal-cord-based organisms!
젠장할!
Bugger it!
'제트파이어'의
위력을 보거라!
Behold the eternal glory of Jetfire!
나를 여기서
벗어나게 해달라!
Prepare for remote systems override!
- 곱게 늙을 것이지
- 안 무서워
-l tell you, this guy did not age well.
-l don't think he's gonna hurt us.
이 문을 열거라!
l command these doors to open.
발사!
발사하라고 했다!
Fire! l said, fire!
빌어먹을!
Bollocks!
- 부품을 갈아치우든 해야지!
- 잠깐!
-Damn these worthless parts.
-Wait a second!
녹이 슬어
걷기도 힘들군!
ltchy, wretched rust in my arse!
박물관 사람들
열 좀 받겠는걸!
The museum is going to be very angry.
Very angry.
저 비행기 잡아라!
We gotta catch that plane.
맞다, 임무수행 중이었는데
그게 뭔지 까먹었네
-Right. l'm on a mission.
-Wait, wait, wait, wait!
- 왜 불러?
- 얘기 좀 하자!
-What do you want?
-Look, we just want to talk!
시간 없다!
임무수행 중이야!
l have no time to talk. l'm on a mission.
근데 여긴
무슨 행성이냐?
l'm a mercenary doom-bringer.
What planet am l on?
지구다
-Earth.
-Earth?
이름 한번 촌스럽군
차라리 '흙행성'이라고 하지
Terrible name for a planet.
Might as well call it "Dirt." Planet "Dirt."
로봇 내전은
아직도 진행 중이냐?
Tell me,
is that robot civil war still going on?
- 누가 이기고 있지?
- '디셉티콘'!
-Who's winning?
-The Decepticons.
- 나 '오토봇' 편으로 바꿨는데
- 어떻게 편을 바꿔?
-Well, l changed sides to the Autobots.
-What do you mean, "changed sides"?
내 맘이지
지극히 개인적인 결정이다
lt's a choice.
lt's an intensely personal decision.
'디셉티콘'처럼
미워하며 살 거 없잖나!
So much negativity.
Who wants to live a life filled with hate?
그럼 '디셉티콘' 편
You mean you don't have to work
안 들어도 돼요?
for those miserable,
freaking Decepticons?
'디셉티콘'은 전 우주를
파괴시키려고 한다
lf Decepticons had their way,
they'd destroy the whole universe.
나 편 바꿀래요
여전사님
l'm changing sides. l'm changing sides,
too, warrior goddess.
- 나 이뻐해줘요
- 귀여운 것!
-Who's your little Autobot?
-You're cute.
'윌리'라고 할래
내 이름 불러봐요!
Name's Wheelie. Yeah.
Say my name, say my name.
눈 뜨고 못 보겠다
What are you allowing
to happen to your foot just now?
얘는 한눈 안 팔아
At least he's faithful, Sam.
너만 바라보는
변태인 거지
Yeah, well, he's faithful and he's nude
and he's perverted.
그만 좀 할래?
Can you just... Can you stop?
새겨들어라
-Hey, what are you doing?
-lt's just something
뭐라고?
to think about. l won't argue with...
What were you saying?
난 '제트파이어'라고 했다!
성질 돋구지 마!
l told you my name was Jetfire,
so stop judging me.
- 보통 뿔난 게 아닌데
- 내가 다혈질인 건
Somebody shit the bed this morning.
-Look at this guy.
-l have issues of my own.
다 엄마 때문이다!
And it started with my mother!
우린 대대로
여기 살았지!
My ancestors
have been here for centuries.
우리 아버진 바퀴셨다
최초의 바퀴!
My father, he was a wheel,
the first wheel.
- 근데 뭐로 변했게?
- 몰라
-Do you know what he transformed into?
-No.
못 변했어!
Nothing!
하지만 굴하지 않으셨지
똥폼 잔뜩 잡고!
But he did so with honor,
dignity, damn it!
Bollocks.
추진장치가 나갔다
My boosters are fried.
서로 돕자
l think we can help each other.
우린 서로
모르는 걸 아니까
You know things l don't know.
l know things you don't know, l do.
아는 거 개뿔
없어 보여
l don't think he knows anything.
Honestly, l don't.
하루 종일
그릴 수도 있어
l could do this all day.
lt comes in waves, these vivid symbols.
계속 떠오르거든
They're symbols, but they're in my mind.
You see, all this is in my mind
근데 이걸
'메가트론'이랑
and Megatron wants what's in my mind.
- '폴른'이란 자가 노려
- '폴른'은 잘 알지
-Him and someone called The Fallen.
-The Fallen? l know him.
날 여기서 썩게 뒀으니까!
'디셉티콘' 원조인데
He left me here to rust.
The original Decepticon.
밑에서 일하기 피곤해
만날 때려부수기 일쑤고!
He's terrible to work for.
lt's always apocalypse, chaos, crisis.
이것도 내 임무다
These transcriptions,
they were part of my mission,
'폴른'이 찾으라고 했지
The Fallen's search.
'단검의 끝'과 열쇠를!
l remember now,
for the Dagger's Tip, and the key.
'단검의 끝', 열쇠가
다 뭐지?
Slow down. The Dagger's Tip? The key?
What are you talking about?
설명할 시간이 없다, 다들 꽉 잡아!
버둥대면 죽는다!
No time to explain. Hold on, everybody!
Stay still or you'll die!
나 아직 쓸만한걸
Well, that wasn't so bad.
딴 행성에
온 건 아니겠지
l just hope we're still on the right planet.
야, 너무 아프다!
Hey, that freaking hurt!
Oh, my God.
세상에!
Oh, God.
맙소사!
이 아름다운 얼굴 좀 보게!
Oh, my God, what a beautiful face.
완벽한 순간인데
하필 내 거시길 깔아뭉개냐
This would be a perfect moment,
except you landed on my testicles.
내려주라
Please, get off.
아이고, 내 뿡알!
God, my balls.
샘!
Sam!
여기가 어디야?
시몬스!
-Where are we? Simmons!
-Hey! Yeah!
웬일이래! 여기가 어디야?
라스베가스 사막이잖아
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
What is this? lt's Vegas.
- 다들 괜찮아?
- 응
-You guys okay?
-Yeah.
라스베가스 같아!
Hey, l think we're in Vegas!
엄청 아프네
나 안 다친게 다행이야!
That really, really hurt.
You're just lucky that l didn't get hurt!
다 죽을 뻔했잖아
People could have gotten killed, okay?
And if l would have gotten hurt,
- 나 털끝하나라도...
- 시끄럽다
-you would have heard...
-Shut up.
내 덕분에
이집트까지 날아와 놓곤
l told you l was opening a space bridge.
lt's the fastest way to travel to Egypt.
귀띔이라도 해주지
When did you... When did you tell us?
You didn't tell us anything.
이집트엔 왜?!
Why are we in Egypt?
건방 떨지 마, 인간아!
눈치는 뒀다 뭐해!
Don't you get snippy with me, fleshling!
You were duly informed!
잠깐 진정하고
말해줘 봐
Can you just stop for a second?
Can you focus?
이집트엔 왜 왔지?
Can you tell us why we're in Egypt
so we can all have a little bit of
semblance of peace of mind?
우리 조상은
수천 년 전에 이미
This planet was visited
by our race once before,
이 행성에
발을 디디셨다
by our earliest ancestors, millennia ago.
우리의 생명력인
에너지를
They were on an exploratory mission
to harvest Energon,
거둬오란 임무였지
the lifeblood of our race.
그게 없으면 우린 녹슬어 죽는다
지금의 내 꼴을 봐!
Without it, we'll all perish, oxidize
and rust, like my wretched self!
서서히 낡아져
죽는 기분을 아나?!
Do you have any idea what it's like
to slowly fall apart and die?
너무 가진 맙시다
꼰대 양반?
Let's not get episodic, okay, old-timer?
기승전결, 알짜만
요약해서 말해 봐요
Beginning, middle, end.
Facts. Details. Condense. Plot. Tell it.
이 사막에 묻힌 우리 조상들은
대단한 기계를 만드셨지
Somewhere buried in this desert,
our ancestors built a great machine.
그건 태양들을 파괴해
에너지를 얻게 하는 거였어
lt harvests Energon by destroying suns.
- 태양들을?
- 파괴해?
-Destroy suns?
-You mean blow them up?
태초에
Yes. You see, in the beginning,
우리의 리더이신
'프라임' 일곱 분은
there were seven Primes,
our original leaders.
우주로 나가 먼 태양에서
에너지를 구하려 하셨지
And they set out into the universe,
seeking distant suns to harvest.
단, 한 가진 지키셨어
생명이 있는 행성은 파괴하지 않는다
The Primes set out with one rule,
never destroy a planet with life,
헌데 그들 중 하나가
규칙을 어기려 했고
until one of them tried to defy this rule.
그는 다름 아닌
'폴른'이었어
And his name forevermore
was The Fallen.
그는 인류를 얕보고
He despised the human race
그 기계를 돌려
전인류를 죽이려 들었지
and he wanted to kill you all
by turning on that machine.
그걸 작동시킬 수 있는 건
전설적인 열쇠인
The only way to activate it
is with a legendary key
매트릭스뿐이었어
called the Matrix of Leadership.
그 매트릭스를 두고
거대한 전투가 일어났지
A great battle took place over
possession of the Matrix.
'폴른'이 다른
'프라임'들보다 강했기에
The Fallen was stronger than
his brothers,
'프라임'들은 그걸
훔쳐선 숨겼어
so they had no choice
but to steal and hide it from him.
매트릭스를 봉인하기 위해
결국은 목숨까지 바쳤지
ln the ultimate sacrifice, they gave
their lives to seal the Matrix away
자신들의 무덤 안에
그걸 넣고 봉한 거야
in a tomb made of
their very own bodies,
그 무덤은
찾을 수 없어
a tomb we cannot find.
이 사막 어딘가에
그 무서운 기계도 묻혀 있겠지
Somewhere, buried in this desert,
that deadly machine remains.
'폴른'은 알고 있어
The Fallen knows where it is
그러니 '프라임'들의 무덤만 찾으면
너희 세계는 멸망하고 말지
and if he finds the tomb of the Primes,
your world will be no more.
어떻게 막지?
Okay, so how do we stop him?
'프라임'만이
상대할 수 있어
Only a Prime can defeat The Fallen.
'옵티머스 프라임'?
Optimus Prime?
'프라임'을 만났나?
So, you've met a Prime?
이런, 위대한 후예를
만난 거로군
Why, you must have met
a great descendant.
살아있나?
지구에 있어?
ls he alive, here on this planet?
날 구하려다 죽었어
He sacrificed himself to save me.
'프라임' 없인 불가능해
'폴른'을 막을 자는 없지
So, he's dead.
Without a Prime, it's impossible.
No one else could stop The Fallen.
그 기계를 작동시킬 수 있는
에너지라면
So, the same energy that's gonna be
used to reactivate the machine,
'옵티머스'를 살릴 수도
있지 않을까?
could that energy somehow be used
to reactivate Optimus
and bring him back to life?
그런 용도는 아니지만
그만큼 강하긴 하지
lt was never designed for that purpose,
but it's an energy like no other.
'디셉티콘'이 날 잡기 전에
어떻게 매트릭스를 찾지?
So, then how do you get us to the Matrix
before the Decepticons get to me?
네 머릿속의 지도
그 기호를 따라가!
Follow your mind, your map,
your symbols.
모래 위에 썼던 게
단서야!
What you carved in the sand,
it's your clue.
새벽빛이 '단검의 끝'을 비추면...
세 명의 왕이 문을 열어줄 것이다!
When dawn alights the Dagger's Tip,
Three Kings will reveal the doorway!
문을 찾거라!
Find the doorway!
어서 가!
Go now! Go!
내 임무를
네가 맡거라
That was my mission.
lt's your mission now.
'디셉티콘'이 나와 널
찾기 전에 가거라!
Go before the Decepticons find me
and find you.
ClA 친구 말이
Okay, here's what my ClA contact says.
아카바 만을
'단검의 끝'이라 불렀대
Ancient Sumerians used to call
the Gulf ofAqaba the "Dagger's Tip."
그거예요
-That's the Dagger's Tip.
-lt's part of the Red Sea.
그게 이집트와 요르단을
칼끝처럼 나눴다고
lt divides Egypt and Jordan
like the tip of a blade.
북위 29.5도, 동경 35도
여기야
29.5 degrees north, 35 east. Here it is.
'옵티머스'도
데려가야죠
First thing we've got to do
is get Optimus to the Dagger's Tip.
지구 반대편에
있는데?
How are you gonna get him
halfway around the world?
전화할게요
l'm gonna make a call.
경찰이다!
We got cops!
나 감방 못 가!
l can't go to prison, guys.
샘, 조용한 데로 숨자
Sam, we got to get off this road
and lay low.
무식한 경찰들!
Man, stupid cops!
숨바꼭질
별거 아니네
This is what's called
blending in like a ninja.
- 떠들면 면상 구겨준다
- 갔어
-Shut up or l'll blend my fist in your face.
-They're gone.
레녹스한테
전화해야 돼
Okay, we're running out of time.
l gotta make the call to Lennox...
전화하면 바로
위치추적 당할걸
You're on the Worldwide Wanted List.
Try calling one base,
they'll track you here in seconds.
- ClA가 쫙 깔릴 거야!
- 걸어요
-ClA is all over this place!
-You're gonna call.
그래, 그게 좋겠다
-Okay. That's a good idea.
-All right.
근데 자꾸...
잡생각이 들어
l mean, l just had my mind
on other things,
이집트 감옥에
갇히는...
like winding up in an Egyptian prison.
뉴저지
트랜스포머 작전팀
21시 출발!
NEST departure, 2100 hours.
기지로 옮기다니
이건 실수야
So, we're shipping him back to base.
This is such a mistake.
소령님
전화입니다
Major Lennox, phone call.
레녹스
건방진 애들이
Lennox, l'm with the kid. The kid. You
know, the one with the attitude, right?
트럭이 필요하대
그 트럭!
We need the truck. The truck.
부활도 가능해
We got a possible resurrection
going on over here.
여기가 어딘지 못 믿을걸
암호는 '투탕카멘'
You're not gonna believe where we are.
Code Tut, as in King Tutankhamen.
장소는
1달러 지폐 뒷면!
Back of a $1 bill.
공중투하 좌표는 북위 29.5도
동경 34.88도, 받아 적어
Coordinates for airdrop, 29.5 north,
34.88 east. Write it down. Write it.
맙소사, 끊는다
짭새가 떴어
Oh, my God. l got to go. Okay.
Heat comes.
Wait, who are you?
나예요
레오!
Wait. lt's me. Leo. Me. Leo. Leo. Leo.
짭새가 와요!
빨리 가요
Cops are coming right now.
We need to go!
Move, move, move, move.
북위 29.5
동경 34.88?
Coordinates, 29.5 north, 34.88 east.
홍해 끝
아카바 만인데요
Tip of the Red Sea. Gulf ofAqaba.
이집트?
거길 오라고?
Egypt? Are you serious?
보좌관님
Sir.
그 거구를 그리
옮긴다 해도
Even if we could figure out a way
to get big man over there,
그 꼬마가 어떻게
살려내죠?
how is this little kid supposed
to bring him back to life?
그건 모르지만
믿어볼 수밖에
Look, l don't know,
but we got to trust him.
다시 말해봐요
Okay, let's go over it again.
새벽빛이
'단검의 끝'을 비추면
When the dawn alights
the Dagger's Tip,
-the Three Kings...
-Will reveal the doorway.
세 명의 왕이 문을 열어준다
무슨 뜻인지 알아?
That's what he said.
You know what it means?
- 아뇨, 아저씬?
- 모르지
-No, what does it mean?
-l have no idea.
난 몰라
검문소야!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Checkpoint. Checkpoint.
여권도 없는데
l don't have my passport.
여권!
Passport!
카메라도 있어요
They got cameras at the top.
진정하고 스파이질 좀 해보자
나만 믿어
All right, chill. This is espionage time.
l can handle it.
나도 아랍 피가
1/36은 섞였어
These are my people.
l'm one-thirty-sixth Arab.
작은 고추가 매운데
무조건 키 크다고 아부해
Great, a fricking Munchkin.
Little people are mean.
Tell him he's tall.
'단검의 끝' 맞죠?
The Dagger's Tip? Right?
이집트, 요르단
거기 가는데
Egypt, Jordan. We want to go there.
우리 가족이에요
얜 내 아들!
Me and my family. This is my family.
This is my son,
또 내 아들, 내 딸
뉴욕에서 여행 왔죠
my other son, my daughter.
We're tourists, from New York.
- 뉴욕?
- 네
-New York?
-Yes. Yes.
50킬로!
Fifty kilometers.
내 중동친구 닮았네
You look like the guy that runs
my falafel stand. Thank you very much.
- 낯이 꽤 익어
- 가쇼!
-l know. l know you from somewhere.
-Go, Yankees!
ClA로 전송해
Put it on the wire to the ClA.
'디셉티콘'들아
꼬마 위치를 알아냈다
Decepticons, boy's location detected.
스타스크림 추적 중
눈에 띄면 안 돼
없는 듯이 굴어야지
Undercover, yo. You got to blend in
with your surroundings.
배경에 녹아들라고
You know, you got to be part
of the landscape.
굉장하다!
외계 로봇 솜씨일 거야
Awesome! l think aliens built that.
Yeah, yeah.
아무렴
가자!
Come on. Move it! Move it!
보초 잘 서고 있어
Guard us. Low profile.
Don't make a scene, okay?
고생 좀 해라
맹한 '오토봇'들아!
Yeah, some of us got work to do!
Dumb Autobots.
트랜스포머 작전팀
도착 6시간 전
내 여친 하기
고달프겠다
Being my girlfriend is hazardous
to your health.
요즘은 위험한 남자가
대세잖아
Yeah, well, girls like dangerous boys.
- 그래?
- 응
-Do they?
-Yeah.
그 말이나 해줘
You might as well just say it.
숙녀 먼저!
Ladies first.
이럴 땐
신사인 척하네
Okay, so tonight you're going to be
a gentleman.
- 매너도 좋으셔라
- 왜 화났어?
-You're really chivalrous.
-Why are you mad at me?
사실은 말이야
나 화 안 났어
You know what?
Baby, l'm not... l'm not mad.
너 죽는 거 막으려고
5천킬로나 날아온 거 알아?
Do you realize that l just flew 3,000
miles to keep you from getting killed?
알지
l know.
나 아님 누가 하겠니?
Who else could be your girlfriend, Sam?
나 엄청 고생했어
Look at the things l go through with you.
근데 이 별 밤에
And now we're underneath the moon
and the stars
아름다운 피라미드를
앞에 두고도
and the three most beautiful pyramids
on the planet
사랑한단 말도
못해주다니
and you still can't even tell me that
you love me.
피라미드
Pyramids.
자꾸 말 돌릴래?
What? Why do boys always
-change the subject?
-Pyramids and stars.
피라미드와 별
-Sam?
-Come with me really quick.
따라와 봐
시몬스, 레오, 일어나!
Simmons! Leo! Wake up!
천문학 책 47페이지
기억나?
Listen, astronomy class, page 47.
Remember the class?
아니, 겨우
이틀 다닌걸
No. l was only in college for two days.
Remember that?
- 일어나 봐
- 왜 그러는데?
-Here. Get up. Up, up.
-What is he talking about?
저 별 세 개 보여?
Okay, you see those three stars?
지평선에 닿은 게
You see
how the last one touches the horizon?
오리온의 띠야
'세 명의 왕'으로 불리는 건
That's Orion's belt,
but it's also called the Three Kings.
이집트 왕들이
그 별들을 본떠
And the reason for that
is the three Egyptian kings
피라미드를 지어서야
who built the pyramids of Giza
built them to mirror those stars,
우릴 겨눈 화살 같지
so it's like an arrow staring us
straight in the face.
동쪽, 요르단의
페트라 산을 가리키는데
They all point due east, towards Jordan.
The mountains of Petra.
엔진고장
We've had an engine malfunction.
특수작전 사령부로 우회!
We're gonna have to divert
to SOCCENT.
비상탈출
준비하십쇼
Flight master, let's lighten the load
and prepare for bailout.
비상?
Bailout? Bailout? Bailout? Bailout?
- 전원 낙하산 준비!
- 비상... 비상탈출?
-All right, team, grab your chutes!
-Bailout like bailout?
- 자유낙하 해보셨죠?
- 당연히 안 해봤지!
-You familiar with the standard MC-4?
-Of course not!
멀쩡한 비행기 두고
왜 떨어져?
l've neverjumped out of
a perfectly good airplane before!
Wait a minute, is this really happening?
-Yeah.
-All right, here we go.
잠깐, 자네 꿍꿍이지?
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
You're behind this, aren't you?
설마요
What are you talking about?
You heard the pilot.
조종사는
허튼 소리 안 합니다
These guys don't mess around.
This is just standard procedure.
전 명령에 따를 뿐이죠
그러라고 하셨죠?
l'm just following orders to the letter.
lsn't that what you said?
군복 벗을 각오나
하고 있게, 소령
You just signed a death warrant
on your career, Major.
왜 이래?
What was that? What was that?
이거 심각한데
가죠
That's not good. Come on.
- 이쪽입니다
- 난 못 뛰어내려
-Right this way!
-l can't jump out of an airplane!
신경성 위염이라고!
안 돼
-l have an ulcer! No, no.
-Come on. lt's okay.
난 못해
못한다고!
l really can't do this.
What are you doing...
이리 오십쇼!
Come here! Come here.
- 자넨 왜 안 입어?!
- 귀빈부터 모셔야죠!
-Why aren't you wearing your chute?
-Because l have to secure the VlPs first.
잘 듣고 똑똑히
기억하십쇼!
Okay, l want you to listen very carefully
and memorize everything that l say.
낙하산엔 GPS가 있어서
곧 구조될 겁니다!
Each chute has a GPS tracker so you
can be found by Search and Rescue.
이 끈은 낙하산을
고정해주죠!
Right next to that's a fabric webbing
called a bridle,
which holds the pin
that keeps the main container closed.
- 듣고 있죠?
- 안 들려!
-Okay, are you listening?
-l can't hear what...
정신차리세요!
-Stop that!
-All right. All right.
보조낙하산이 부풀면서
All right,
when the pilot chute inflates into the air,
낙하산이 펴집니다!
it pulls the pin and opens the main.
빨간 건 예비용이니까
Red's your backup, blue's your primary.
파란 걸 당기세요!
아주 세게요!
l want you to pull the blue.
l need you to pull it really hard!
지금 말고요!
비행기에서 펴면 어쩝니까!
Not now, we're on the plane,
you dumb-ass!
- 작별인사 해요?
- 아니, 그냥 가던데
-He say good-bye?
-No, he didn't even say good-bye.
장군님, 명령만 내리시면
General, we're loaded and ready.
5분내로 시행됩니다
You give us the go, and we'll be ready
to press in five minutes.
- 좋았어
- 이것 좀 보시죠
-Excellent.
-Sir, you need to see this now.
레녹스-북위 29.5/동경35.88
집중포격 준비
- 이 좌표의 위치는?
- 이집트에 낙하 중입니다
-Have we checked these coordinates?
-Egypt, sir.
-They're airdropping in.
-You've got to be kidding me.
설마!
뭔가 아나 본데
He knows something.
만일을 대비해서
총력지원하게
We need to be ready to back him up
if this thing goes hot.
알았다
Copy that.
ClA에서
꼬마를 찾았답니다
ClA just got a hit on the boy,
거기서 160킬로
거립니다
1 00 miles from the location
on that little note there.
사태가 심각하군
lt's getting hotter.
여기 어딜 텐데
lt's gotta be around here somewhere.
이 스케일 보여?
You see the size of this?
- 이거 봐
- 굉장한걸
-You see this?
-Spectacular.
놀랍군
저거 봐
Amazing. Look at that.
여기 어딘데
-lt's here somewhere, guys.
-Yeah, why?
'블랙버드' 할아버지 말을
'Cause we're trusting Grandpa Blackbird
어딜 봐서 믿냐?
who doesn't even know
what planet he's on?
그래도 이게 가장 큰
문이긴 하잖아
ln his defense, this is the biggest
doorway l've ever seen in my entire life.
좋아요
후딱 둘러보죠
Okay. Well, that's great.
Let me do a quick search, all right?
없네
Nope. Ever cross your mind, guys,
고고학자들이
다 쓸어갔을 리도 없고
that archeologists
have been here before?
There's nothing here.
고고학자들이
다 쓸어갔을 리도 없고
인생은 실망의
연속인 거야!
Real life is heartbreak, despair, kid.
막상 무지개 끝에
가보면
Sometimes you get to
the end of the rainbow
신기루일 때도 많지!
and the leprechauns went
and booby-trapped it!
엄마랑 살면서
큰소린!
l'm listening to you?
You live with your mother!
- 끝난 게 아냐
- 다 끝났어
-lt's not over.
-lt is over. lt's done.
왜 네 말을
들어야 돼?
Why are we still listening to you,
little punk-ass?
뭘 해줬다고
l mean, what you ever done for us
except ding my rim?
'메가트론'을
죽였잖아
Killed Megatron. How about that?
어차피 다시
살아난걸, 뭐
Well, he didn't get the job done,
you know what l mean,
'cause he's back now...
- 왜, 무섭냐?
- 못생긴 네 얼굴이 무섭다!
-Are you scared?
-Scared? Scared of your ugly face!
못생겨?
우린 쌍둥이인 거 몰라?
l'm ugly?
Well, we're twins, you stupid genius!
덤빌 테면 덤벼봐!
Bring it, then! Get off me!
- 얼굴을 찌그려주지!
- 진하게 손봐주마!
-l'll change your face around!
-l'll get all up in that ass!
말로만?
Bring it!
얘들아!
Guys!
- 맛이 어떠냐?
- 안 아프거든
-You like the way that feels?
-That didn't hurt.
You like that, don't you?
이거 좀 놔줘!
-Come on, Bumblebee!
-Bumblebee, listen.
막 팽개치냐!
Now, that's rude.
세상에, 그 기호야
Oh, my God. The symbols.
'범블비'!
부숴
Bee! Shoot it.
이거 봐
-Check this out.
-Look at it.
와아!
Wow!
'제트파이어'가 말한
시쳇더미야
These are the bodies
Jetfire was talking about.
'프라임'들의
무덤이군
The tomb of the Primes.
야!
Yo!
매트릭스다
The Matrix.
No.
수천 년의 세월에
가루가 되었군
Thousands of years, turned to dust.
이게 끝은 아닐 텐데
This isn't how it's supposed to end.
들었어?
Hear that?
미공군 C-17기야!
US Air Force! C-1 7s!
- C-17이 뭔데요?
- 살려내는 건 불가능해
-What's a C-1 7?
-You can't bring him back, Sam.
-There's nothing left.
-Look! Look around you.
봐!
이렇게 끝내자고
We didn't just go through everything
we went through for no reason at all,
그 고생을 한 건 아니잖아
to just have it end like this.
이유가 있어서 왔지
There is a reason that we are here.
목소리며 기호가
날 이끌었다고
The voices and the symbols in my head
led us here for a purpose.
다들 날 쫓아오는 건
Everyone's after me
because of what l know,
내가 이걸 해낼 수
있기 때문이야
and what l know is that
this is going to work.
- 어떻게 알아?
- 믿음이 있거든
-How do you know it's gonna work?
-Because l believe it.
날 비행기에서
내려줘
You best let me out of this plane.
어서 떨궈라
샘!
Dropping the big boy. Sam!
그 가루로
살려낼 수 있겠어?
You think you can bring him back to life
with that pixie dust?
그럼요
Absolutely. Let's go.
가자!
Go!
우리 편
안 다치게 해
Let's move it.
Remember, they're friendlies.
'옵티머스'를 덮어줘!
Cover Optimus!
마을을 보호하라
Secure the village.
Get those cases down here.
곳곳에 저격병을 배치해!
l need snipers and Stingers up high.
10톤이나 되는
로봇 시체를 옮겨준 만큼
So, we just dropped off 1 0 tons of
dead robot in the middle of nowhere.
꼬마가 잘해내야 할 텐데요
l hope this little kid know
what he's doing.
그러게
Yeah, me too.
타겟 포착, 노란색
4킬로 지점!
Got a visual! Yellow team! Four clicks!
조명부터 쏴!
Pop flare!
- 저기야, 불꽃 보여?
- 바로 저기야!
-That's them, right there. See the flare?
-Right over there! See it?
꼬마 발견
Sam!
하느님, 제발!
Oh, God. Please, God! Please.
레오, 그만 해!
Leo, stop freaking out. Stop freaking out.
쟤 입 좀 막아!
Shut this guy up, huh?
제발 살려주세요!
-Please, just let me live, just let me live!
-Shut up and let him drive!
됐어!
-Just stop screaming...
-All right, that's it!
참아줄 수가
있어야지!
l can't take that guy anymore.
먼지 속에 숨어!
Hide in the dust! Use the dust!
찢어지자
'범블비', '디셉티콘' 유인해
We've got to split up.
Bumblebee, you're the decoy.
난 '옵티머스' 맡을게
You lead the Decepticons away,
all right? l'm gonna get Optimus.
난 쌍둥이들하고
총알 유인할게
l'll help draw their fire
with Huey and Dewey there.
넌 군인들한테 가
You get to those soldiers.
- 그 가루가 효과가 있길 바라
- 고마워요
-l hope that dust works, kid.
-Thank you.
방향을 돌렸어요
돌아오고 있다고요
He's turning around. He's coming back.
He's coming back.
내게 맡겨
lt's up to me.
사랑하는 조국에게
버림받은 사나이가
One man, alone,
betrayed by the country he loves,
조국을 구하다니!
now its last hope
in their final hour of need.
운전의 묘미를 보여주지
한 수 배워라
Prepare to be driven like never before,
by the maestro.
- 이봐요, 가지 말아요!
- 넌 꿈도 꾸지 마
-Hey, hey! Don't go nowhere! Drive.
-You'll never make it, kid.
-l'm coming with you.
-Bravery will only get you so far.
용감한 자만이 승리한다!
전기 총 쐈던 빚은
갚아야죠
You tased me, okay? You owe me!
l'm going.
좋아, 인정해주지
Okay, okay. That was a test.
You passed. All right?
외계 문신으로 도배를 했군요
공군이 아녜요
That thing's got alien tattoos all over it.
That ain't Air Force.
- 이건 뭐지?
- 누구 있나?
-What the hell was that?
-Anyone copy?
나와라!
-Anyone there? Who's up?
-Copy?
- 고장 났습니다
- 통신이 마비됐어
-Radio's down.
-lt's dead. Comms are down.
전자기파가 세요
EMP burst.
사막 한복판에서
고생깨나 하겠군요
l see how this day is going
in this godforsaken desert.
뭔가?
Yes, sir?
- 소령이 낙하하랬습니다
- 알고 있네
-Major Lennox told me to pull the cord.
-l know, sir.
여기가 어느 나라죠?
Well, what country am l in right now?
미국이오
United States.
미국일 리가 있나!
내가 미국에서 왔는데!
No, not the United States.
l'm from the United States.
여기 애들
아주 무식해요!
I'm in the middle of nowhere
surrounded by donkeys.
우리의 친구, 갤로웨이인데
전혀 기뻐하지 않는군
Well, that was our good friend,
Galloway. He's less than pleased.
엉뚱한 연락은
오는데
How is it that we can't reach our men,
정작 내 부하들은
이집트 사막에서 뭘 하는 거지?
but he can reach me
from some random Egyptian desert?
없어요
Nothing.
SOS를 크게 써서 불태워
위성으로 보이게
Right, go burn an SOS. Let the eye in
the sky know we need some help.
- 네
- 구식으로 해보자
-Yes, sir.
-Okay, boys, old school time!
Pop some more flares
so the kid can find us.
꼬마 보게 불 더 지펴
저 봐, 저기야
3킬로 거리야
Look. There it is.
We got a couple of miles.
레녹스 팀의 양자암호
장치는 아주 최신인데
Lennox's team has the latest
in quantum crypto gear.
누가 말해주겠나?
왜 간단한 무전도 안 되는 거지?
Can somebody tell me why we can't
establish simple radio contact?
각 주파수로
시도 중입니다
We're hailing them on every frequency
and mode in the book, sir.
위성 고장입니다
Our satellites in the area have
gone blind. We're working it, sir.
젠장, 뭔가 잘못됐어
말이 안 되잖아
Damn it. Something's not right.
lt doesn't add up.
요르단 공군력 좀
빌려보지
Contact the Jordanians, see
what air assets they've got in the area,
이집트 장군
살람한테
and get Egypt's General Salam.
이집트 영공에
무인정찰기 띄운다고 해
Ask him to clear some USV overflights
in Egyptian airspace.
마냥 앉아서
기다릴 순 없겠어!
We need an assist
in confirming visuals now.
'프레데터' 띄워
Scramble Predators now.
V-1, 고속상승!
V-1 , rotate.
1.5킬로는 더 가야 돼
We still have a mile that way.
힘내
Come on.
이쪽이야
This way. This way.
- 나뿐이야, 나 혼자라고!
- 그만 좀 해요
-One man, alone...
-Stop saying that!
조국이 배신해도!
...betrayed by the country he loves!
혼자라니, 그럼 난!
Oh, my goodness.
l'm in the car, okay? You're not alone.
긴장 풀어
나 고수야
Just relax. You're with the maestro.
이제 안 따라와요
l don't think he's still following us.
그건 네 생각이고
That's what you think.
대장님, 나쁜 소식을
전해서 죄송하지만
Master, sorry to be the bearer
of bad news,
'프라임' 시신이
도착했습니다
but the soldiers brought
the body of Prime.
꼬마가 매트릭스를 가졌다
The boy must have the Matrix.
'옵티머스'와 접촉 못하게 해!
We cannot let him reach Optimus.
'디셉티콘'들아
공격하라!
Decepticons, begin our assault!
공격이다!
We've got incoming!
총력 공격한다!
We got a whole lot of fight
coming our way.
- 몇이나 돼?
- 열셋쯤 됩니다
-How many?
-About 1 3 of them.
이거 상황이
안 좋은데요
This ain't good. This ain't good.
크게 당하겠어요!
We're about to get our asses whupped.
B팀, C팀!
Bravo-Charlie, kneel!
'디셉티콘'들은
샘을 찾고 있다!
All right, those Decepticons
are searching for Sam.
'옵티머스'를 되살릴
뭔가가 있는 듯하니
Whatever he has, he thinks
it'll bring Optimus back to life,
그앨 찾아
'옵티머스'한테 데려오자!
so our mission is to find him
and get him to Optimus.
정찰팀을 꾸리자!
All right, we're gonna draw fire
from the left flank. l need a scout team.
내가 맡지
l'm leading.
'알씨'와 '아이언하이드'에
합류해!
Go up through the middle
with Arcee and lronhide!
샘을 찾으면
All right, when you see
the precious cargo,
녹색 연기 피우고
저 기둥 쪽으로 와
l want you to pop green smoke and
come back through those pillars.
우린 매복한다, 출발!
We'll have the ambush set. All right.
Let's go. Move out!
'OK목장의 결투' 봤냐?
You ever see that film
Gunfight at the O.K. Corral?
-With Burt Lancaster and Kirk Douglas?
-No, why?
- 버트 랜커스터랑 커크 더글라스 나온?
- 아뇨, 왜요?
-Looks like we're right in the middle of it.
-ls that good?
- 딱 그 상황이라
- 해피엔딩이에요?
A lot of people died.
싸그리 죽었어
- 숨어!
- 숨어... 숨어야죠!
Hide!
- 가자!
- 난 몰라!
-Vamonos, amigos!
-Oh, my God!
- 수그려!
- 으아, 세상에!
-Hit the deck!
-Oh, my God!
샘!
Sam, Sam.
l don't think they saw us.
우릴 못 봤나 봐
앉아
Get down. Get down. Get down.
Okay. Listen.
잘 들어
Once it's clear, we run for Optimus
as fast as we can, okay?
여차하면
'옵티머스'한테 뛰어가
이게 잘 안 되면?
What if it doesn't work?
잘될 거야
lt's gonna work.
- 혹시 안 되면?
- 분명히 돼, 꼭 될 거야
-What if it doesn't?
-lt's gonna work. lt'll work.
꼭 될 거야
어서 가!
뒤로 가, 뒤로
Up, up, up!
올라가!
Get ready to jump!
뛸 준비해!
1킬로 남았어
군인들은 우리가 온 걸 몰라
We got a half-mile. l don't think
the soldiers know we're here.
- 후퇴!
Fall back!
- '아이언하이드', 가운데로!
- '아이언하이드', 피해!
-lronhide, up the middle!
-lronhide, move it!
Let's go! Go, go!
가자, 어서!
Devastator!
'디베스테이터'!
오도 가도
못하게 됐어요!
We're trapped! There's nowhere to go.
We're gonna die.
죽을 거면
남자답게 죽어야지!
lf we're going out, we're going out
like men, understand?
이런 잡것을...
Look at this mother...
이 몸이 나서주지!
Mean robots suck!
꽉 잡고 있어!
Hang on! Hang on, okay?
- 스키즈, 꽉 잡아!
- 안 돼!
- 시몬스!
- 꽉 잡아!
-Simmons!
-Don't let go!
놓치지 말고 꽉 잡아!
Hang in there, l got you! Just hang in.
나 죽기 싫어!
l don't want to die!
쿵푸식 버티기 권법!
Kung fu grip, boy. Kung fu grip!
내가 좀 끈질기지!
You ain't getting me!
He dead. He got so ate.
죽었어
먹혔다고
-Who's your daddy now, huh?
-He got all ate up.
- 내 덕에 산 거 알죠?
- 한입에 삼켰어
등잔 밑이 제일
어두운 법이지
The only safe place is right under it.
달려
-Run at it. Run for its feet! Move it!
-Yeah.
- 발쪽으로 뛰어!
- 알았어요!
You should've never eaten me!
l'm gonna bust your face up!
감히 날 꿀꺽해?!
면상을 찌그려주마!
Oh, my God!
우와, 세상에!
덤빌 상대가 따로 있지
당해봐라!
Nobody mess with me! ln your face!
Keep fighting, Mudflap!
힘내라, 우리 편!
Oh, my God!
맙소사!
이야!
Nobody messes with the twins.
쌍둥이 건들면
큰코다쳐!
잡았다!
l got you... My bad!
- 앗!
- 나의 실수!
아야, 얼굴을
때렸겠다?!
Man! You shot me in the face!
- 아래로 숨어!
- 그래, 숨어
-Stay under it!
-Yeah, stay under it!
Come on.
'램피지', 덫을 놔라
Judy!
여보, 이리와!
-Sam! Sam!
-What?
- 샘!
- 뭐?
Sam! Sam!
샘, 샘!
Sam!
-Sam!
-Dad!
아빠!
Wait, wait!
잠깐만!
Please listen to me!
l want you to run! Run!
잘 들어!
어서 도망쳐!
Dad, just stop!
They don't want you, they want me!
아빠, 그들이
원하는 건 저예요!
-Oh, God!
-Wait!
Sam Witwicky.
샘 윗위키...
Don't hurt them. This is what you want.
You don't want them.
해치지 마
원하는 건 이거잖아
-Go! Go!
-Please, stop!
- 가!
- 제발 그러지 마!
-Stop!
-Listen to your father!
아빠 말씀 들어!
Just get out of here!
도망쳐!
Just don't hurt them.
l know what you want.
해치지 마
원하는 게 뭔지 알아
Just go! Just go!
그냥 가!
And l know that you need me
because l know about the Matrix.
나도 원하겠지
매트릭스에 대해 아니까
-Don't do it, Sam...
-Please, Dad.
하지 마!
-They're going to kill us all anyway!
-Here's what you want, right here.
- 어차피 우릴 죽일 거야!
- 넌 이걸 원하잖아
Bumblebee!
'범블비'!
Kill him, Bee. Kill him.
'범블비', 죽여
-Stay tight, Ma.
-Come on. Get in here.
- 가만 있어요
- 여보, 이리 와!
-Bee?
-Yeah.
- '범블비'?
- 그래
-Hey!
-l don't know
일단 도망치고
보자고!
what's going on, but we've got to move!
There's got to be a way out of here!
무슨 방도가 있겠지!
Judy, get back, get back, get back.
여보, 물러서!
Against the wall! Against the wall!
Against the wall. Against the wall.
벽으로 붙어요!
Bee! Bumblebee!
'범블비'!
You get them somewhere safe,
all right?
안전한 데로 모셔가!
You've got to get in the car
and get to safety.
어서 타요
No, this isn't up for discussion!
아니
그럴 순 없어!
-You're my son! You're my son!
-l know.
넌 내 아들이야!
-Dad...
-We all go together!
가도 다 같이 갈 거야!
-Listen...
-We're all going together!
Dad, stop, okay? Get in the car.
He's gonna get you to safety.
아빠, 어서 타요
안전한 데로 모실 거예요
You know, you run.
You don't stop, you don't hide, you run.
도망쳐요
서지도, 숨지도 말고 가요
You hear what l'm saying, okay?
l'll find you when you're safe.
곧 따라갈게요
-No.
-You've got to let me go, Dad.
- 싫어
- 절 보내주세요
-You have to let me go. You have to.
-Ron.
- 가야 해요, 부탁해요
- 여보...
Ron. Ron, let him go.
여보!
보내줘
You come back! Come on.
꼭 살아 돌아와!
Ron! Mikaela! Mikaela!
여보, 미카엘라!
-Go with my parents.
-l'm not gonna go without you.
- 같이 가
- 너 두곤 못 가
Move to cover!
엄호해!
We got Jordanians!
요르단 헬기예요!
We got help!
도우러 왔군!
Down!
숙여!
You okay, soldier?
괜찮나?
We're gonna help you, soldier. Let's
get these wounded clear of the bird.
어서 부상자를
옮기자!
Stay still. Stay still. Don't move.
그대로 가만있어요
You all right, young man?
You have a radio?
괜찮나?
무전기는?
Hey, kid, it's been nice knowing you.
Remember what l did for my country.
꼬마야, 반가웠다
나의 애국심을 기억해다오
This is my moment.
나 아주 비장해
You're crazy!
미쳤군요!
ETA to station, two minutes.
도착 예정시간 2분 전!
-Put it on the main screen.
-Sir. Yes, sir.
스크린에 띄워봐
Predator 01 .
'프레데터 01'
Shit, it's a trick.
큰일났군
Commence Operation Firestorm.
Send everyone.
'파이어스톰' 작전 개시
-Get those Marines on the ground.
-Roll in strike packages...
- 해병대 파견해
- 최대한 지원해
Task Force Ripper, execute Lightning.
'라이트닝'작전 실시!
-Spotted Sam!
-Sam!
- 샘을 찾았다!
- 이봐, 샘!
lronhide!
'아이언하이드'!
Follow us to the pillars.
We'll take you to Optimus.
'옵티머스'한테
데려다줄게
Get out, Sam! Get to the pillars!
도망쳐!
기둥으로 가!
Let's go.
가자
Oh, God. This is it. The pyramid's built
right over the machine.
하필 피라미드를
기계 위에 지을 게 뭐람?
lf they turn that machine on,
no more sun.
저 기계를 틀면...
태양이 사라지겠군
Not on my watch.
그렇겐 안 되지
어림없는 소리야!
USS Stennis. ldentify.
여긴 '스테니스'호!
Where the hell are you?
Watching the Weather Channel?
거기 어딥니까?
날씨 방송 봐요?
SportsCenter?
l Dream of Jeannie orsomething?
아님 스포츠?
코미디?
We got 300 satellites up there.
Where the hell are all our men?
위성이 300개나 있는데
우리 안 보여요?!
ldentify yourself.
신분을 밝히시오
What is your name, sailor?
이름이 뭐요?
Wilder, Captain of the
USS John C. Stennis aircraft carrier.
와일더, 항공모함
'스테니스'호 함장이오
Okay, Captain Wilder.
좋소, 와일더 함장
This is Agent Seymour Simmons
of Sector Seven.
이 몸은 '섹터7'의
시몬스 요원이오
There is the mother
of all non-biologicals
태양을 폭파하려는
getting ready to blow up our sun.
로봇이 있는 판국에
Do you want to have a throwdown
about my lack of clearance
쪼잔하게 따질 거요?
or do you want to help save
a gazillion lives?
인류를 구할 거요?
All right, Agent Simmons. l'm listening.
원하는 걸 말하시오
시몬스 요원
Five clicks west of the Gulf,
아카바 만의
서쪽 5킬로 지점에서
we got ourselves an alien
remodeling a pyramid.
외계 로봇이
피라미드를 부수고 있으니
Our one hope is a prototype weapon
called a rail gun,
마하 7 속도로
강철 미사일을 쏘시오
-shoots a steel projectile at Mach 7.
-That's classified.
상부허가가
필요하오
Don't talk to me about classified,
all right?
허가 얘긴 하지도 마시오
알았소?!
Now, if you've got a battleship
in the Gulf, which l know you do,
아카바 만에
전함 있는 거 아니까
you tell them to ready that weapon!
무기 장착시켜요!
Contact destroyer USS KIDD.
구축함 '키드' 연결해
Alpha Team, flank left!
A팀, 좌측으로!
This way! Move it!
이쪽이다, 서둘러!
-Where do you need us, sir?
-Protect those in the line of fire.
어디로 갈까요?
Let's go! Go!
가자, 어서!
Give me your Comms. Come on. Epps!
무전기 좀!
엡스!
Right now, we need air support, ASAP!
속히 공중엄호
해달라!
Have troops in contact 20 miles
northwest. Radar contact.
북서쪽 30킬로에
병력이 있다
Proceed to 88 Alpha Sierra...
B-1 , snap 090.
B-1, 750킬로짜리
폭탄을 발사하라
You are approved to drop your
2,000-pound JDAMs.
-What you got?
-l couldn't get to them, sir.
어때?
They're 600 meters away
and they're heading right for the pillars.
기둥 쪽으로 가고 있어요!
All right. Precious cargo's coming!
샘이 오고 있다!
Move!
뛰어!
Curse you!
Sam! Spotted Sam!
샘?
샘을 찾았다!
- 엡스, 가자!
- 투-투 엄호사격
-Come on!
-2-2 covering fire.
Two civilians, 1 2 o'clock!
12시 방향에 두 명!
Cover for us!
엄호하라!
Hold the air strike!
We're rescuing civilians!
공습 유지하라
민간인을 구출하겠다!
Keep firing!
계속 발사해!
Come on! Mikaela!
이리와!
미카엘라!
Come on! Get in here!
어서!
이리와!
Look who showed up.
이게 누구야!
You better have a good reason for us
to be here.
괜히 부른 게
아니길 바라
-Where's Optimus?
-He's right over there,
- '옵티머스'는요?
- 저쪽 너머에 있어
across the courtyard.
-l got to get to him right now.
-Not with an air strike coming.
- 가야 돼요
- 공습 중이라 안 돼
l have to get to him right now.
당장 가야 돼요!
Go. Back, back, back, back.
물러서
-Go.
-Listen up...
Okay.
좋아, 가만있어
lncoming!
간다!
Stick the landing.
착지실력을
보여주지!
Behold the glory of Jetfire!
'제트파이어'의
위력을 보시라!
Now let me show you how we brought
the pain in my day!
내가 왕년 솜씨 좀
발휘해주지!
l'm too old for this crap.
나이는 못 속여
Keep going, man, 1 5 rounds of fighting.
계속해라
누가 오래 버티나 보자
l am directly below
the enemy's scrotum.
내가 있는 곳은
놈의 거시기 밑이자
25.7 meters above sea IeveI,
29.32 north.
해발 25.7미터
북위 29.32!
-Kill track, 5205...
-Target acquired.
- 어서 발사해
- 조준 완료!
-Killing track.
-Two, one...
2... 1...
Fire!
발사!
Yeah! Yeah!
B-1's time on target, 30 seconds.
2,000-pound JDAMs inbound.
B-1, 30초 후 정 위치
폭탄 장전!
We're gonna make a break through
the B's on my command, okay?
내 명령대로 움직여
You guys stick with me, you
understand? You stay on my ass.
나하고 같이 행동해
붙어다니라고!
-1-1 tally orange smoke.
-l hope these F-1 6s got good aim.
- 오렌지색 연기!
- 조준을 잘해야 할 텐데요
-Yeah? Why is that?
-l told them to hit the orange smoke.
- 왜?
- 오렌지색에 쏘랬어요
You mean that orange smoke?
오렌지색이면 여기?
lt wasn't my best toss, okay?
잘 안 던져져서요
-Viper, thunder.
-Run!
- '바이퍼', '썬더'
- 뛰어!
lncoming!
폭탄이다!
Come on!
Sam!
샘!
Run!
Die!
Sam!
샘!
Hold your fire!
발사중지!
Sam!
Stay back! Mikaela, stay back!
물러서!
미카엘라, 물러서!
Fucking do something!
어떻게 좀 해봐요!
-Sam! Sam!
-Sam! Sam! Sam! Sammy! Sam!
- 샘, 샘!
- 샘, 엄마 아들!
-Let me go!
-Come on, you got to move.
- 이거 놔요!
- 저리 비켜!
-You got to move, come on.
-We got no pulse.
맥박이 안 잡혀
Starting CPR.
심폐소생술!
-l have to see my kid! l got a son...
-Sammy!
- 내 아들을 봐야 돼!
- 샘!
Sam!
-Clear.
-Ready to shock.
- 물러서
- 실시!
-Clear!
-Ready to shock. One, two, three.
- 물러서!
- 실시, 1, 2, 3!
Do it again!
다시 해!
No!
Okay, listen to my voice.
l love you and l need you.
내 말 잘 들어
사랑해, 곁에 있어줘
Please. Please, come back to me.
Sam, please!
제발, 내게 돌아와
샘!
l love you.
사랑해!
Where am l? Where am l?
Am l dead? Am l dead?
여기가 어디죠?
내가 죽었나요?
We have been watching you
a long, long time.
우린 널 지켜봤다
아주 오래 전부터
You have fought for Optimus,
our last descendant,
'옵티머스'를 위해 싸웠지
그는 우리의 마지막 후손으로
with courage and with sacrifice,
the virtues of a leader,
용기와 희생이란
리더의 미덕을 갖췄다
a leader worthy of our secret.
우리의 비밀을
짊어질 만하지
The Matrix of Leadership is not found,
it is earned.
매트릭스는 찾는 게 아니라
얻는 것이다
Return now to Optimus.
'옵티머스'에게
가거라
Merge the Matrix with his spark.
매트릭스를 그의
스파크와 결합시켜!
lt is, and always has been, your destiny.
여태 그래왔듯
지금도 그게 네 숙명이다
Sam!
l love you. l love you.
사랑해, 사랑해
Boy, you returned for me.
꼬마야
날 위해 와줬구나
A living Prime.
살아있는
'프라임'이라...
l don't believe it!
믿을 수가 없군!
My Matrix!
내 매트릭스!
Get up! Get up! Get up! Get up!
일어나요, 어서!
Get up, Prime!
일어나십쇼, '프라임'!
Oh, no.
안 돼...
He's turning on the machine!
You got to stop him! Get up!
기계를 켜려고 해요!
어서 막아요!
Optimus!
'옵티머스'!
Fallen, my master.
'폴른'
사부님이시여
My brothers could not stop me from this.
내 형제들도 나를
막을 수 없었다
Yes, now l claim your sun.
이제 너희 태양을
손에 넣겠다!
-Move!
-Enemy target, top of pyramid. Engage!
피라미드 위에
적 발견!
Engage! Engage!
공격하라!
ln moments, we'll be at firing strength.
곧 싸워야 할 겁니다!
All my Decepticon life, l never did
a thing worth doing until now.
'디셉티콘'으로 사는 동안
난 가치 있는 일을 못해봤다
Optimus, take my parts
'옵티머스'
내 부품을 통해
and you will have a power
you've never known.
더 큰 힘을
얻을 것이다
Fulfill your destiny.
네 숙명을 완수하라
Jolt! Electrify!
'졸트', 전기!
Transplant those afterburners.
추가 추진장치
이식해!
Let's roll.
출동하자
Fire mission on the pyramids.
피라미드 조준!
This planet will be dark forever.
이 행성은 어둠에
갇힐 것이다!
Die, like your brothers!
죽어라
네 형제들처럼!
They were your brothers, too.
당신 형제이기도
했다!
Starscream!
'스타스크림'!
You picked the wrong planet.
지구를 택한 게
잘못이다
Give me your face.
끝을 내주겠다!
l rise.
난 승리하고...
You fall.
넌 패배한다!
No, no.
안 돼
Not to call you a coward, Master,
대장님이
그렇단 건 아니고
but sometimes cowards do survive.
때론 겁쟁이가
살아남는 법이죠
This isn't over.
이게 끝은 아니다
lt took all this for you to tell me that
you love me.
이 상황까지 와서야
사랑한다고 하네
You said it first.
네가 먼저 말했다
Thank you, Sam, for saving my life.
고맙다, 샘
내 생명을 구해줬구나
Welcome.
별말씀을요
Thank you for believing in me.
절 믿어줘서
고마워요
Our races united by a history
long forgotten
우리 종족은 잊혀진
역사 속에서 하나가 되었고
and a future we shall face together.
장차 미래와
마주하게 될 것이다
I am Optimus Prime,
나 '옵티머스 프라임'은
and l send this message so that our
pasts will always be remembered,
이 메시지를 보내며
우리의 과거가 항상 기억되길 바란다
for in those memories, we Iive on.
그 기억의 힘으로
살아갈 테니까
So glad you could join us,
Professor Einstein.
다시 왕림해주셨네
아인슈타인 교수
Yeah, l was kind of busy.
조금 바빴어요
Okay.
진짠데